<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

	<title><![CDATA[Code Journey]]></title>
	<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/"/>
	<updated>2013-09-17T13:52:57-04:00</updated>
	<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/</id>
	<author>
		<name><![CDATA[Wenson Tsai]]></name>
		
	</author>
	<generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Day #1]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/17/day-number-1/"/>
		<updated>2013-09-17T12:30:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/17/day-number-1</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>The morning was spent shaking off nerves with laughs, dark jokes, and dancing as we threw ourselves in a course of improv.  It was a great way to get out of our shells, look dumb in front of a room of strangers/new friends, and get us in the right mindset to be team-players.</p>

<p>Lessons to take away:</p>

<ol>
<li><p><strong>Yes, AND&hellip;</strong>   &ndash; Always accept what your fellow player gives you, AND try to give them something back that they can work with, a little gift.  &ldquo;No&rdquo;/questions take the energy somewhere else unproductive with the flow</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Always show up</strong>   &ndash; No matter if you are scared, unprepared or what, just show up and create in the moment from there.  That&rsquo;s the most important.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Help them out</strong>   &ndash; When you see a fellow player in trouble, jump in and save them.  Don&rsquo;t let them die alone out there!</p></li>
</ol>


<p>The afternoon was just as invigorating as we jumped straight into setting up our Fullstack profile pages off a minimal template.  It was HTML/CSS in action, as well as a challenge in vision &ndash; to create a stylesheet, requires understanding how to work within the defaults/habits of HTML/CSS.  It was a leap into madness with divs, nested divs, floats, and the beauty hack of the &ldquo;clearfix.&rdquo;  This was all after setting up Github and learning how to commits as well.</p>

<p>I got most of the page looking like it was supposed to, but then spent the last 2 hours trying to get some links to hug right and to the bottom.  It just wasn&rsquo;t meant to be.  As a last ditch effort, I tried to renest one of the divs by putting the main quote into a class of its own, and leaving the links outside to text-align: right.  THEN, I noticed a div tag that I forgot to close.  I closed that, then scooted a few things around, and the page just went to shit.  Everything became unaligned, and CTRL-Z became the very bestest friend I could have ever had.  Backsteps off the lava cliff jump.  And so, it wasn&rsquo;t perfect, but it was something.</p>

<p>I rushed out fast for the first time in a week &ndash; headed off to the Apple Store to replace the battery on my brand new Macbook Air.  Here&rsquo;s to 12 hours of battery time.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
</feed>
