<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

	<title><![CDATA[Code Journey]]></title>
	<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/"/>
	<updated>2013-10-02T23:13:35-04:00</updated>
	<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/</id>
	<author>
		<name><![CDATA[Wenson Tsai]]></name>
		
	</author>
	<generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[fancy seeing u here]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/02/day-number-13/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-02T22:52:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/02/day-number-13</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>The Active Record/Sinatra/SQLite collabo.. wait, did we start it yesterday or fresh today?  Who knows anymore.  I just had to check my own blog, to write my own blog.  Head in a fog, log, bog, smog, brog.  Today was fun.  We made weird worlds, and I put chips and salsa everywhere, and David put guac, and Nimit hi-jacked my macbook like a Somali pirate and I&rsquo;m that new Tom Hanks movie where he grows a beard and keeps order over his seamen.  Surely persistence and the drive to discover is how you learn things (so that&rsquo;s how you get good at things!).</p>

<p>Week 3 of the program, rolling along &ndash; thinking that we are already 25% of the way through the course, puts the fear in me like a lake of fire and gnashing of teeth next to the devil could never instill.  YOU ARE ALREADY &frac14; OF THE WAY THROUGH WITH YOUR WEB DEV IMMERSIVE SOON YOU WILL TAKE THE SKILLS YOU HAVE ACQUIRED FIND A JOB AND START WORKING WITH SAID SKILLS ON THE DAILY FOR MONEY.  This statement, is so fucking scary, it could be used in your favor to convert me to any religion/religions/causes/cults/sex-cults/porno-cage-dungeons of your heart&rsquo;s desire.  Yes, I will do porn if you just keep yelling that sentence at me.  I&rsquo;m so scared, yes, I&rsquo;m ready to shoot!!</p>

<p>In less scary news, or actually, rather debatable, check out what I made at school today mama!</p>

<p><a href="https://dry-tundra-6501.herokuapp.com/person/new">https://dry-tundra-6501.herokuapp.com/person/new</a></p>

<p>Come on in, have some chips n salsa in the foyer, kick up a shoe or two, pee in my double golden toilets (made of real gold, not that plated stuff), take a bounce or three in my double moon bounces, and check out some real meat in the dry-age-room/muscle dungeon.  But only if you dare.  Don&rsquo;t eat spaghetti squash in front of your keyboard while you explore these wormholes, soldier.  Also, go ahead, put in your name (I&rsquo;ll never see it), create some rooms to your heart&rsquo;s content (I will see these), and make some connections between those rooms to keep Wenson Stack World spicier than a mala pepper gone down the wrong throat path.</p>

<p>Don&rsquo;t be shy.  Here, to help things along, I&rsquo;ll tell/show you about myself.</p>

<p><img src="http://mayaday.files.wordpress.com/2010/03/funny-asian-face.jpg" title="JACKSON FROLIC" alt="Jackson Frolic" /></p>

<p>name:  Jackson Frolic <br>
description:  gum drops and jelly breams!<br><br></p>

<p>** breams are a type of fish like a snapper.  i kno how 2 type ohkay</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[day n nite]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/01/day-number-12/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-01T23:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/01/day-number-12</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>Today, we had our 3rd Fullstack Dinner, and it was pizza.  Grandma&rsquo;s pizza, Grandpa&rsquo;s pizza, White pizza, mushroom pizza (which no one touched inexplicably) &ndash; the pizza game be diversified.  The day was one with a good flow &ndash; we first learned about the internets.  The internets is busy, and it keeps passing stuff back and forth like basketball drills to keep us seeing things and un-revolty.  The US government was down today (effing ridiculous), but hey, it&rsquo;s fine when you can watch people do things on Brobible.com (mind sanitize).</p>

<iframe src="http://wensontsai.github.io//player.vimeo.com/video/14570497" width="500" height="375" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p> <p><a href="http://vimeo.com/14570497">Packet Flight: RickRoll @ 12X</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/carlosb">Carlos Bueno</a> on <a href="https://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p></p>

<p>Then we moved on to designing this multi-room portal site pulling in Sinatra, Rails(Active Record), SQL, and HTML/CSS which was pretty cool, cause it lets people come onto your site, and then create a room and name things.  Of course, the first room I named was the toilet, because every good space including a wormhole, needs a toilet (keep it hyperspace-clean, son!).  My butt cheeks be allergic to anything that&rsquo;s not gold even when I&rsquo;m space-dimensional-contiuum-irrespective-morphing/traveling.</p>

<p><img src="http://maison.trouvetout.ca/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/hong-kon-golden-toilet1.jpg" title="golden toilet" alt="golden toilet" /></p>

<p>I went back in time to fetch a 24k gold spouted butt-washer add-on with adjustable pressure/temperature controls.  Worth the risk of having to fight dinosaurs/aliens/zombies.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[munday]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/30/day-number-11/"/>
		<updated>2013-09-30T23:51:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/30/day-number-11</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s a bit of a toss, between life and the immersive.  No one said it would be easy.  No one said this.  And, certainly, no one promised that weekends would be rejuvenating.</p>

<p>Today&rsquo;s work was comprehendable enough.  We got to know the mystical black magic that is Active Record (AR) in Ruby on Rails.  It speaks a sort of yoda backwards SQL, and it does a bunch of weird things behind your back (well, not super weird, but certainly AR has a bit of the flair for the theatrical), oh, and did I mention, sir/madaam AR cares about your use of singles vs plural, even when it&rsquo;s only referencing your class objects as such for its own entertainment?  To not do so, would be uncivilized.</p>

<p>Oh, I&rsquo;m coming apart on a munday funday.  The week is a young-day.  Better keep strong.  Today, my pair-partner came down with a sickness, and now family-sized dispensers of Purell are on every desk in the house.  Keep the energy up, keep the health meters up, the mana and the mojo.  Rest, all you have to do is rest, and it&rsquo;ll be all right.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[death of pig-latin]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/28/day-number-10/"/>
		<updated>2013-09-28T16:18:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/28/day-number-10</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>I thought it would take me the next 5 years of my life, but with a shit-ton of help and explanation, failed thought process/approaches, hipchat support, sacrifice of a saturday, housecat jealousy, pure grudgery sprinkled on top, I re-wrote the code for the pig-latin testfirst.org problem, got it to work, and also understand it.</p>

<p>Arrays to strings to arrays to arrays to strings to goddamnit computer, why cant you just think the way I think, and we can be friends and share the same underpants?  You don&rsquo;t wear underpants.</p>

<p>Pig-Latin is dead!!</p>

<p>5 years of life has come back to me, and now I&rsquo;m thinking of skipping off to enjoy a Saturday night instead of working all the way through.  I am not a computer &ndash; just yet.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[grit]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/26/day-number-9/"/>
		<updated>2013-09-26T23:01:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/26/day-number-9</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>We wrapped up the Ruby/SQL query middle-layer build exercise today.  It was good.  Way envious of what my partner can just see, solve, and code.  While my brain pulls blanks, he&rsquo;s got gears turning, and with the gear-turning you got stuff to try.  I like trying stuff.  Running code, whether right or wrong, may be a distant cousin of slot machines.  Gimme more code for me nickel slots.</p>

<p>We then got into groups to present about classes vs instances, class methods vs instance methods.  They say teaching is the best way to learn.  To teach, you got to feel like you got it under wraps.  Then to bring someone outside of yourself to understanding, well that&rsquo;s a whole nother thing.</p>

<p>I believe in giving.</p>

<p>Not as some tax write-off, but as a human activity we all should be involved in.  To be honest, it doesn&rsquo;t even matter what you give.  It&rsquo;s just important to reach outside of yourself, help others, be connected &ndash; there&rsquo;s a true joy in it.</p>

<p>Information is definitely one of the easiest things to give.  But not necessarily one of the easiest to receive.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m feeling pretty lucky watching the teachers at Fullstack.  It turns on the lights in that teacher part of me I nurtured in Japan.  I would have stayed as late as possible or done about anything to help my students grow and understand.  Few rewards are better than being there to usher someone along and change their lives.  I get why in traditional Chinese society, teachers and intellectuals were the most respected social class.  I get why being a teacher in Japanese society pretty much means you are a public pillar of society and a parent to your students for life.</p>

<p>A good teacher will inevitably change the lives of their students.</p>

<p>To believe in someone when they had no faith, to shine a light where they knew not to look, a good teacher gives themselves &ndash; the student and teacher are one &ndash; their growth is your growth, their achievement, your achievement.  We all run on limited time in this life.  Time is our most precious resource.  How else can you feel but grateful for another who spends their minutes improving yours?</p>

<p>I feel lucky that we are the first class at Fullstack.  I know from my own experience, I was able to give the most to the very first graduating class I taught.  Routine and the tear of putting yourself out there over and over can wear even the best.  It&rsquo;s definitely better to be Taiwan than Korea **.</p>

<p>Thank you for the information and the guidance.  Thank you for your dedication, time, faith, support, and encouragement.  It is an inspiration.</p>

<p>Believe you me, I will hold up my end of the deal.</p>

<p>** When Japan was trying to put an empire together to compete with the &lsquo;civilized West&rsquo; (ironically out of a fear of being colonized themselves) they planned to make Taiwan their model first colony.  They pumped infrastructure into there, and although there was conflict, it&rsquo;s quite a stark contrast from when Japan tried to colonize Korea.  Taiwan still has a soft spot for Japan until this day, where as revenge on Japan has been a fire under Koreans for the past half century.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[are we human, or are we object]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/25/day-number-8/"/>
		<updated>2013-09-25T21:14:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/25/day-number-8</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>Today was pleasant.  We wrapped up the sqlite3 workshop we had begun.  I dig it, man.  Inner joins are just like crappy 80&rsquo;s arcade versions of mah-jong (ain&rsquo;t got nothing on the real tiles).  You match up pairs and they disappear.  You want the win? you match up the faces &ndash; pretty much for joins, you got to be as indirect as possible.  You match up two obviouses, just so you can get your in-obvious column.  I can appreciate the mystery and the behind-room-divider finesse.</p>

<p>After we got a handle on SQL commands, we dove back into Ruby, turning each table into a class object, and columns into attributes.  We were to build the middle layer for Ruby to interact with SQL &ndash; building a helper.</p>

<p>It was around then while working through some discrepancies that I came to realize how meta everything was getting.  It used to be just data, basic containers to keep that data, keys to access that data, but now we were dealing with objects.  Objects are only objects in so much as you can imagine a container in the paper of your mind.  We were beyond information you can scribble in a notebook, or wrap in neat curly braces.  Objects.  Are objects even real?  Do objects care if we feel pain?  The information, the words you had before, they&rsquo;re thrown into objects and turned into mere attributes.  Attributes of the object!  What is this &lsquo;object&rsquo;?  A blender for all things real?  How cold!  Your name, your tastes, they have meaning, personality &ndash; in a curly bracket, square bracket, parentheses, they are still themselves, just in a room.  But, in objects &ndash;  now, they were part of the machine.  Emotionless attributes now.  Accessed as so.  Mere markers, of what used to be.</p>

<p>And, right then and there, I had an existential breakdown.</p>

<p>Are we human, or are we object?</p>

<p>I mean, I&rsquo;m just a mere instance of the human class (think human factory).  I run methods like eat, walk, love, make_babies, make_poo, ponder_the_meaning_of_life, laugh, flirt, talk_shit.  I can make_the_world_a_better_place taking arguments like giving, or caring, or I can run methods steal, or murder(with_knife) or destroy(with_emotional_abuse).  And many more pre-programmed actions.</p>

<p>You ever done these online personality quizzes, or done the Myers-Briggs Type Indicator full-on with in-depth explanations regarding your tendencies, world perspective, thought processes, and intuitions?  I read one once just a few months prior that had me ALL FIGURED OUT.  Down to the most secret and fundamental of my instincts that I had put energy into developing, practice into trusting.</p>

<p>It was as if I was exactly where I was supposed to be, just that I, the one it was happening to, was the only one that didn&rsquo;t know.</p>

<p>I, me, whatever, exerting effort, right at the cusp of believing in progress, manuevering new directions, but everything I discovered, someone some thing already knew I would think, act, make sense this way, even as I was convinced I was doing everything of my own will and volition.  A simple text, I&rsquo;d never seen, already knew I would be trying to do so and predicted it.  It freaked me the fuck out.</p>

<p>Was it feasible that our destinies and fates could be so thinly veiled?  That the train and the track could glide ever so blatantly eye-to-eye?  How could it be, that life seems so original, so real, subjectively, yet be so easily uncovered and predictable?  I felt so ordinary, so cliche, so played-out, so kitsch.  Was I human, or was I object?  And, was I this way all along?  Why didn&rsquo;t anyone tell me?</p>

<p>Or,</p>

<p>was I supposed to feel this way, at this very point in time, as the fates and destinies and programming purposely pre-aligned &ndash; which was first, the chicken, the egg?  Could a chicken lay the very egg it is hatching out of simultaneously, just in time to lay another egg, which contains none other than itself?  What if the eggs were not chicken eggs at all, but duck eggs, with a purple-grey dead duck baby inside, and the Vietnamese friends you were drinking with told you to spoon lime juice with black pepper/chili paste onto its face and slurp &ndash; would it taste like cajun crawfish, even though it&rsquo;s neither cajun NOR crawfish??</p>

<p>How
fucking
predictable.</p>

<p>Hello World!
I&rsquo;d like you to meet someone:</p>

<p><img src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v416/yelofngr/screenshot.png" title="wenson bot" alt="wenson bot" /></p>

<p>ruby new_life.rb</p>

<p>::::::&hellip;&hellip;.. meep bloop blop bloop meep mrop breep.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&v=RIZdjT1472Y
" target="_blank"><img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/RIZdjT1472Y/0.jpg"
alt="are we human, or are we dancer" width="480" height="360" border="0" /></a></p>

<p>NoMethodError:
  undefined method &lsquo;DANCER&rsquo; for # _Rspec::Core::ExampleGroup::Nested_2::Nested_1:0x007ffda8042938>#./spec/requests/user_pages_spec.rb:9:in &lsquo;block (3 levels) in top(required&rsquo;</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[inspiration transfer]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/24/day-number-7/"/>
		<updated>2013-09-24T21:21:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/24/day-number-7</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>Rough.  That&rsquo;s all I can really say.  The going is rough.  It&rsquo;s full-on Rocky over here without the benefit of a Netflix summary telling you everything&rsquo;s gonna wrap up okay at the end of 1:45hrs run-time.  Driving rough.</p>

<p>We finished up the Rspec blackjack testing/coding endeavor today, didn&rsquo;t gain too much more ground on getting greens and drowning red failure statements.  Even after all was explained and done, I still felt drowny and heavy all up in the chest.  We then moved on to learning SQL.  Oh syntax, you are the worst ex-girlfriend of them all, I swear.</p>

<p>The crotch punches continued deep into dusk, with little to no tea-refill breaks (we were out of water tanks for the dispenser so I put some green tea in some seltzer water.  a bubbly gassy fail.) the abuse remained a flurry until our Fullstack Dinner ++ today where we were treated to a delicious and balanced meal from Digg Inn, loved ones and friends joined us, mostly I think, so they could lock in a mental/emotional picture for imagining where their significant other/loved ones are when they don&rsquo;t ever see them in person again until December.  It&rsquo;s busy up in here.</p>

<p>I was so tired and defeated, but soon summoned to life.  The two girls in the class beckoned me over to sit between them.  The other Taiwanese-American guy in the class mentored me about my life.  Apparently he was a movie producer on the side, all the while having his hands in the tech VC world.  Very interesting, and unexpected.  I spilled a bit of my past lives, and there we were in the middle of a long table, talking shop in that weird snooty entertainment industry way, making jokes about crafty and trail mix.  I always did love being on set.</p>

<p>He buckled down tough-love style, but I was listening.  His message? to focus down what exactly I wanted to get out of this experience &ndash; also, what I wanted to get out of the life I had remaining.  This intensity was really happening at the same table we ate bagels and cream cheese every morning, except with people all around watching the spectacle, but they didn&rsquo;t really exist anyway.  He gave me a lot to think about.</p>

<p>As people came and went, another group formed, and these two other students began talking about their dedication to working on personal projects.  Unexpected inspiration again.  I felt electrified to hear of them wishing this place had a shower so they could work around the clock to get stuff done.  We are already 10% of the way through the program, one said.  He&rsquo;s right.  Better get on it.</p>

<p>I will come up with a passion project of my own to spearhead the learning and networking and NASA fall-out transfer technologies and make me portfolio pretty and give me lots of fire when I talk about things I care about, get the toes and fingers all wet and sticky again in the cauldron of life and creativity and imagination and possibilities and yes.  I think there will be a capstone project before we finish anyways, and it will be fantastic to have a vehicle to push everything forth as I leave gravity behind and burn, burn, burn it up through the atmosphere.</p>

<p>The last few short and sudden hours have reminded me that eyes keep focused solely on the road, it miss the scenery.  The unseen benefits of a road trip are many.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[sock full of nickels]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/23/day-number-six/"/>
		<updated>2013-09-23T19:51:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/23/day-number-six</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>The dimensions of variables inside variables is increasing.  Today, we worked on Rspec testing/coding a program that pits a player vs a dealer in blackjack with the ability to write/load different strategies for game play.  It trucked along, the violence, and the bloodshed ~ they beat me over the head, they brutalize me!  Complaints of police brutality?  This is code brutality &ndash; growing pains still growing on day six.  But, the tolerance for it has grown as well.  It&rsquo;s become less personal.  The sailor begin to understand the waves.  I went home around the usual dismissal for one of the first times since the course begun.  Knowing your limits is vital for keeping on pace and riding the distance.  Get, git, get &lsquo;em tomorrow.  Power posing in bathrooms across the nation!</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[code or be coded]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/20/day-number-5/"/>
		<updated>2013-09-20T23:31:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/20/day-number-5</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p><img src="https://gs1.wac.edgecastcdn.net/8019B6/data.tumblr.com/5ae10f924c1f1473693df1fe98bf1e1d/tumblr_mtgiw7qmjl1ryra09o1_1280.jpg" title="murky seas" alt="murky seas" /></p>

<p><img src="https://gs1.wac.edgecastcdn.net/8019B6/data.tumblr.com/0852a0ef576aa69f5f3dd4a728f9106d/tumblr_mtgiuzLoJP1ryra09o1_1280.jpg" title="all the drama of a gladiator fight in a 6x8 rectangle and you're riveted as hell" alt="riveted" /></p>

<p><img src="https://gs1.wac.edgecastcdn.net/8019B6/data.tumblr.com/72342ab6118b80da91d7fd5f05e3f31d/tumblr_mtgit1ArXt1ryra09o1_1280.jpg" title="the tee-shirt game will never be the same" alt="tshirtgame" /></p>

<p><img src="https://gs1.wac.edgecastcdn.net/8019B6/data.tumblr.com/e075a21932c3849740c12cdf71f65aad/tumblr_mtgit1ArXt1ryra09o2_1280.jpg" title="we came, we cried, we cried some more" alt="team onionz" /></p>

<p>I witnessed the sly smile first hand from David, and heard the &ldquo;Why&rsquo;d you tell him?&rdquo; from Nimit, as they leaked joy that was the hackathon today.  Really, all anyone ever has to say, is ROBOTS.  Even I know that.  ROBOTS are a free pass to boner time.</p>

<p>What I didn&rsquo;t know was that Legos have advanced to an unimaginable level of complexity.  I&rsquo;d really like to meet the kids that can do this shit.  A room full of grown ass people were bent, slapped &ndash; some resembled psychiatric ward regulars staring off into nothing, jabbing little lego joints into pegs into balls into wings into what looked like pre-fused hair clips and chewy swords &ndash; this continued for hours.  Our group fared no better.  In fact, I was convinced we were the worst.</p>

<p>Today was legions different than my pair-programming experience yesterday.  Our group was unfocused, lost, trudging, achingly dead in the mud.  I was frustrated with them.  I was frustrated with myself. I&rsquo;d really really wanted to win.  It seemed impossible now.  I mean, if they&rsquo;re not into it, they&rsquo;re just not, right?  I took a breather on the rooftop and contemplated defeat.</p>

<p>The other groups seemed to super have it together.  The potential burn of embarassment would be difficult.  An entire day&rsquo;s worth of work, and not anything to show for except a robot with swords for hair.  It says in huge print &ldquo;Ages 10+&rdquo; right on the box.  Fucking genius kids with their little sweat-shop-perfect hands.  The outside change of scenery opened up just enough of a gap to sneak through &ndash; I softened.  Maybe everyone wanted to work harder, but were just burnt to a crisp at the end of this first week.  It was Friday.  And, I was exhausted too.  Maybe today, texting for one of the teammates was necessary &ndash; family stuff?  maybe he was going through a breakup or something.  Who knows.  It didn&rsquo;t matter, they were still good people to me.</p>

<p>I went back in.  After getting some advice and understanding the rules of the game, threw out a complete hackjob of a plan, and then got to making it work.  The goal being for the robot to run around, collect cans, and move them outside the border, I figured we could just run diagonals, bouncing off all the borders, sweeping the cans out and win on speed &ndash; desperate solutions for desperate times.  The robot remained inexplicably hobbled for the next hours &ndash; I loudly vowed I would run into the ring like a crazed overprotective mother, kicking cans in every direction.  &ldquo;Do you know how hard my baby has worked on this?  Stop laughing!  Don&rsquo;t make me come over there!!&rdquo;  Plan B:  The Tiger Mom solution would ensure knocked cans, and this way our defeat, though still hideously embarassing, would be at least memorable.</p>

<p>Then, a funny thing happened.</p>

<p>One of David&rsquo;s CTO friends showed up and offered to help us.  Then David jumped in to help us.  Our team member ranks had grown to 6 or 7.  Then our team began to pull together.  The robot division expanded on the idea of better sweeper arms that made the difference at the last minute.</p>

<p>Then, this absurdist theater cockfight began &ndash; a live feed on the wall.  I must tell you, maybe it was the delusion-inducing fatigue, or the 1.5 beers, but it was exciting and riveting as hell.  These 4 runs had the drama, tragedy, and comedy of Roman gladiator bouts.  I can&rsquo;t even explain it.</p>

<p>Then.  We won.  Team Onionz, who aspired to crush the competition into tears, instead finding themselves in tears, found new tears of relief, surprise, gratefulness and joy for the undeserved, unexpected help and results.  My winner&rsquo;s ring pop was broken but so sweet nonetheless.</p>

<p>Then, a beer spilled on my brand new Macbook Air (breaking it in as a true tool and not just some cool-status ornament).  Then.  I ate tons of raw broccoli.  And then, David&rsquo;s mom dropped science on me.</p>

<p>Never quit, the wise lady told me.  All you have to do, is never quit.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[week 1 wrap for Dave & Nim]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/20/week-1-wrap/"/>
		<updated>2013-09-20T09:46:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/20/week-1-wrap</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<h4>What is the most interesting thing you learned this week?</h4>

<p>The most interesting thing I&rsquo;ve smuggled into the toolbelt this week is the realization that any motion is always better than no motion.  What I mean is, when you are stuck on a problem, you&rsquo;ve been staring to the point where the back of the eyes are strangely hot like your optic nerve is going to just explode out the back of your skull, when you are doubting everything you&rsquo;ve ever believed in and wondering if going home and crying in the shower will truly &ldquo;make it all go away,&rdquo; in those sweltering moments of deep isolation, your best option is to always keep it moving.  Search online for a solution.  Pick up a pen and draw diagrams, flow-charts, break down your thought process.  Ask someone.  Go back to tutorials and start coloring with numbers again.  Anything.  Just don&rsquo;t sit there and let that steam build up to the point where the lid must blow off.  It&rsquo;s a dance, a dance within yourself to keep searching, to keep creative, to never quit, to never die.</p>

<h4>What kind of things are you struggling with?</h4>

<p>I feel like I am playing a giant game of catch up.  I feel unprepared and wonder if I may be overextending myself.  I wish I had another few slow months to really lock in the basics covered in the pre-work.  I struggle with syntax and little things like where in a loop the array loader needs to be.  I forget to put &lsquo;end&rsquo;s sometimes.  Rspec confuses me and I think it may be evil.  Rspec may be evil.  I have no idea what it wants and it&rsquo;s never happy.  Conceptually, git is still sounding like the matrix to me.  But, I&rsquo;m working on it.  I&rsquo;m learning a lot, and when piling things on so it soak in and osmosize &ndash; I know it supposed to hurt a bit &ndash; kinda like when you water drought-ridden arid soil &ndash; the first few moments are mostly water running everywhere except down.  I&rsquo;m with it.  Mostly, I wish there was another me, and we could github our brains and merge our learning so I could get some extra sleep, do a little more nothing, even pick up some drum sticks and do some basic patterns.  Please find a way to clone me, then github our brains.</p>

<h4>What learning techniques are working for you?</h4>

<p>Everything.  You cats are great!  I&rsquo;m so glad this isn&rsquo;t a scam!  Hahaha.  Coming back to the US and hearing about this severe job demand/supply gap and 3month immersives in a field new to me, many people were skeptical like, can this be true?  Do these guys really know what they are doing?  After I send the deposit, show up on my friend&rsquo;s couch, will I follow the address on first day of class to a pretzel stand in the Bronx and have to call CBS&rsquo;s &ldquo;The Lookout&rdquo;?  No.  I&rsquo;m thoroughly enjoying everything that&rsquo;s been going on.  I find the balance of self-struggle, self-discovery and communal group/pair solution resolution tactics to be very fruitful.  The improv lessons have also stayed with me (I wrote about it in the Day1 post below), and I value the interconnected nature of all this.  I want to continue to learn how to be competitive, aim for the best within myself and for everyone around, without losing perspective on end-goals or my own personal values.</p>

<h4>What are your thoughts about pair programming?</h4>

<p>I had a great time yesterday and found it to be an extremely enjoyable and enlightening process.  I wrote about it more in the post below.  My partner and I were even wondering at one point, did you guys purposely put us together knowing our skillsets at this current moment, or were we giving you guys too much credit?  Hahah.  Please keep the credit.  I learned a lot about how there&rsquo;s always spaces for you to help the project along, fill in the gaps.  When my partner got too lost in the details of trying to understand API functions, I would try and shift gears so we could continue to make progress in finishing the work.  And, it really felt like floating yesterday (a rare sensation seeing as it&rsquo;s been a bloodbath through the Testfirst exercises).  We finished very early on, with seemingly little pain or effort.  We joked about how we had become addicted to struggle like a wife in a domestic violence relationship.  Punch me so I can feel alive!  That&rsquo;s a horrible joke, I&rsquo;m sorry.  But, really, things can be smooth, flow, be fun, and still work right.  It happened yesterday.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[scoping]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/19/day-number-4/"/>
		<updated>2013-09-19T21:30:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/19/day-number-4</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>Today was fun.  We started off in pairs to work out a ruby/csv/html/erb/gem cocktail collab that would get us mass-emailing, and mass-texting long-lost friends and family to go check out our octopress blogs ~ this blog right here.  Maybe we were drunk off the power of knowing we could soon be spamming the crap out of the White House, bringing down governments, facilitating coups and peoples&#8217; revolutions, or downright quivering, peering down the slide to darkness as we pressed &lsquo;return&rsquo; each time running the code &ndash; each time understanding this could be the end of all friendships/pleasant human relationships as we know it.  Now that I know how, it will take all the self-restraint in the heavens, all the self-control in the universe, to not spam the shit out of you all every day, my loved ones.</p>

<p>First time out working with a partner, I was teamed up with an ex-pro-gambler/trader, a real genius builder.  We made a great team, for my contributions seemed to weigh more in seeing larger picture motifs, a macro-scope, at least today, while he had a tendency to get locked into the intricacies, the minutiae of the code, micro-scope if you will &ndash; these things he readily admitted to me.  And, although we spent much time bonding over a variety of topics including potential start-up ideas, rebel pirate currency potentialities, and our love of experiencing new food/cuisine, we still managed to breeze through the work as if it was no sweat.  So much so, I constantly feared we were skipping something large in our work.</p>

<p>David talked about pair-programming in being a crash course in scope &ndash; in navigating and in driving (we shared one computer), in seeing across the entire vista, and in locking down telescope-style.  This got me thinking about so many other things.  For focus and an awareness of scope is a vital concept.</p>

<p>There are some really bright and interesting people around me.  David and Nimit, the two founders/owners/teachers, also beam genuine &ndash; they&rsquo;re funny, generous, sharp as fuck, and almost make me think twice about why I fought entering the 9-to-5/typical working world/money/career world so hard when I first left college.  Certainly, not everyone in the working world ends up in middle-management with sweat-stained short-sleeve dress shirts, a collection of ugly ties, a friendly-enough-but-passively-aggressive wife, the 1.5 kids, infinite mortgage, incessantly pestered with the marrow-deep kind of trapped/addicted-to-comfort suburbian veneer which constantly nags if you truly know what being alive is anymore.</p>

<p>Here, there is a hunger.  There is a lust.  Aspirations.  Dreams.  Youth.  Renewal.  There is a hope.  An excitement.  A robust drive.  I feel it within myself as well.  If the previous 5 year block of my life were soft pats and warm hugs from the universe, this last year and a half has been slave-lashings and Muy Thai jumping knees to the kidneys.  Blood in the urine, is nothin more than Red No.10 in your seltzer.  Blood is in the mind.</p>

<p>And here I am.  And here we are.  We are taking the leap and the skip and the jump.  Never lose sight of how far you&rsquo;ve come, where you want to go, and how you want to go to where you want to go.</p>

<p>Even as you fly, keep your preciousness close.</p>

<p>Keep your eyes well on you.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[I will be better today]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/18/day-number-3/"/>
		<updated>2013-09-18T23:27:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/18/day-number-3</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>I said it over and over on the train.  No little programs will destroy me.  So, I may not have a deep technical background, so, I may not have much experience with this.  So, I may not have finished the pre-work yet, and class has already started (believe you me, I wish I&rsquo;d gotten through it all with time to spare, but when doors open, they blow open.  your job is to step through).  Pig-latin is not the end of me.</p>

<p>And so, off to the races.  Unbelievable, it&rsquo;s only day 3.  I&rsquo;m a native New Yorker now.  And a Wall St. banker.  Complaining about long lunch lines at the 1pm rush, talking with Yonkers accents.  BONNKAAZZZ &ndash; like the guy in the elevator yesterday, who Jorge unfortunately said &ldquo;hi&rdquo; to out of kindness, and in a small 3x5 box, moving upwards at a rate of 10ft/hr, he complained about how the microphone on his smashed phone was a mess, and he had to use headphones in order to talk &ndash; in his words, this, &ldquo;a living hell.&rdquo;  New York&rsquo;s a different world.  Talking with headphones is a severe deal breaker, take note, kids.</p>

<p>Solutions were given today for the Testfirst.org problems yesterday.  After yesterday&rsquo;s owning, I was feeling discouraged.  Things got a lot better after I managed to solve a few problems by my own, and now the guy next to me was looking at my answers to get some green test throughs.  David explained the &lsquo;yield&rsquo; method in greater detail, after dropping the science on answers, and I felt much, much better.  After class tutorial small group study sessions?  Yes, please.  As many as you got.  I&rsquo;ll be there.</p>

<p>We got a new project to work on that will take us the rest of the week, a few hours before go-home.  I have not even touched the haiku problem yet from yesterday.  I want to crack at it.  And there&rsquo;s so much pre-work I still want to do, and I want to do the testfirst problems over as well.  So much to do, not so much time.</p>

<p>I have fallen into the NYC pace of non-stop, much like a small child leaping backwards into a mountain of laundry, on a perched but soft bed.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[peaks need valleys]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/18/day-number-2/"/>
		<updated>2013-09-18T22:12:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/18/day-number-2</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>Day two, we started off getting our github/Octopress pages configured and set up.  Hit some snags early on, and it felt like the entire day was all catch up.  The afternoon was spent going through Testfirst.org&rsquo;s Ruby Rspec exercises.</p>

<p>This was extremely confusing at first, since Rspec has its own language, and you must read through it, figure exactly what it is looking for, name your files, classes, methods appropriately, to pass the tests.  What also confused me majorly was not having to print to screen, not having to write the code to finish &ndash; just barebones methods, classes were sufficient.  Cause as you know &ndash; methods always return the last value!</p>

<p>After lunch, catch up became a trudge through Vietnam jungle mud with angry charly in the trees &ndash; problems became immovable, and the brain liquified.  By 4:30pm I was pretty much baked.  With the gracious help of others around, I hacked on and on and always made sure to wrap my head around the principles more than anything else.  Syntax.  Pssh, suck it syntax!!</p>

<p>The day would come to be marked by the pig-latin problem.  Write a method that will take a phrase, separate that into words, turn each word into pig-latin, then pump it back out as a phrase.  Simple-sounding enough right?  No.  Not at all.  This problem haunted and broke me over and over until Day 3&rsquo;s explanation in the morning.</p>

<p>Day two was a solid 12 hours.  I don&rsquo;t remember the last time I went this hard.  It&rsquo;s been a while.  We also had our first Fullstack Dinner tonight, which was good, but brief, as we all had to get back to work.  Back to work!</p>

<p>I got home around 1030pm, couldn&rsquo;t leave pig-latin alone &ndash; worked another 2 hours, drawing diagrams, scribbling notes, then crashed out, still confused.  Super burnt.  Super frustrated.</p>

<p>Well, mountains look highest next to the deepest valleys.  I&rsquo;m sure some wise dude with a beard once said.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[Day #1]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/17/day-number-1/"/>
		<updated>2013-09-17T12:30:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/17/day-number-1</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>The morning was spent shaking off nerves with laughs, dark jokes, and dancing as we threw ourselves in a course of improv.  It was a great way to get out of our shells, look dumb in front of a room of strangers/new friends, and get us in the right mindset to be team-players.</p>

<p>Lessons to take away:</p>

<ol>
<li><p><strong>Yes, AND&hellip;</strong>   &ndash; Always accept what your fellow player gives you, AND try to give them something back that they can work with, a little gift.  &ldquo;No&rdquo;/questions take the energy somewhere else unproductive with the flow</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Always show up</strong>   &ndash; No matter if you are scared, unprepared or what, just show up and create in the moment from there.  That&rsquo;s the most important.</p></li>
<li><p><strong>Help them out</strong>   &ndash; When you see a fellow player in trouble, jump in and save them.  Don&rsquo;t let them die alone out there!</p></li>
</ol>


<p>The afternoon was just as invigorating as we jumped straight into setting up our Fullstack profile pages off a minimal template.  It was HTML/CSS in action, as well as a challenge in vision &ndash; to create a stylesheet, requires understanding how to work within the defaults/habits of HTML/CSS.  It was a leap into madness with divs, nested divs, floats, and the beauty hack of the &ldquo;clearfix.&rdquo;  This was all after setting up Github and learning how to commits as well.</p>

<p>I got most of the page looking like it was supposed to, but then spent the last 2 hours trying to get some links to hug right and to the bottom.  It just wasn&rsquo;t meant to be.  As a last ditch effort, I tried to renest one of the divs by putting the main quote into a class of its own, and leaving the links outside to text-align: right.  THEN, I noticed a div tag that I forgot to close.  I closed that, then scooted a few things around, and the page just went to shit.  Everything became unaligned, and CTRL-Z became the very bestest friend I could have ever had.  Backsteps off the lava cliff jump.  And so, it wasn&rsquo;t perfect, but it was something.</p>

<p>I rushed out fast for the first time in a week &ndash; headed off to the Apple Store to replace the battery on my brand new Macbook Air.  Here&rsquo;s to 12 hours of battery time.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
</feed>
