<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

	<title><![CDATA[Code Journey]]></title>
	<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/"/>
	<updated>2013-10-19T01:34:31-04:00</updated>
	<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/</id>
	<author>
		<name><![CDATA[Wenson Tsai]]></name>
		
	</author>
	<generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[joy life beauty youth]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/19/day-number-25/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/19/day-number-25</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>The ebb and flow of intense emotions and experiences takes me up and leaves me at sea.  The sight of land is a luxury no one can expect &ndash; the rising and setting sun will simply have to do.  My friend, they talk about connecting the dots only in hindsight.  It&rsquo;ll all make sense then, like some tiny islands, when you hop lead you to the main piece, the big show, the motherland.  They talk about fumbling forth, fingers grasp fistfuls of darkness.  They, talk about many things.  When you live, the voices have nowhere to go, or maybe they are close, but your ears cannot process them as the wind rushes by and through your body, a just cracked window in a car makes an epic soundtrack &ndash; living a bit reckless is better than thinking cautious riding pine &ndash; at least I say.  And through it all, through this all, that&rsquo;s what I still say.  Bold.  I know.  Self-assured.  Cocksure.  Sure.  I feel young, and all things possible.  The grim and the grime of lesser times cannot hold on much longer.  It just can&rsquo;t.  And then on and on, it&rsquo;ll go.  To the next adventure lined up to see.</p>

<p>Today, was great.</p>

<p>Sometimes, people are scared to say shit is great.  They fear that maybe, it actually doesn&rsquo;t qualify as great.  Perhaps people around them will think they have shit standards, because what they proclaimed publicly as GREAT, was actually SHIT.  They cast doubt to say so also because, maybe, they think, the amounts of greats we have is limited, and if you keep having GREATs, then all the shit days leftover will come tumbling down and crush your spine, making you a paralyzed shitty cyborg living a life that&rsquo;s worse than death itself, that&rsquo;s why you always say shit is mediocre!  Just alright.  At best, meh!  Although, secretly inside, it was kinda really fucking good man, and you know it.  Shhh, don&rsquo;t let the fates know, or else they&rsquo;ll start distributing strife to balance the scales!  This is not the justice we seek.  Let the fates do what it do.  Your job is to be great, to experience as many great moments as you possibly can, to feel great as much as you possibly can.</p>

<p>Today, I was treated to a tour of WeWork offices today, dynamic, electric, packed with dream-chasers, start-ups, boutique operations, artists, fashionistas, free beer, free arcades, lots of glass with marker scribble, 30th floor New York views, and conference call phone booths.  Then, I had fish friday (king fish at Veronica&rsquo;s Kitchen food truck (the red sannnper is better)).  Then, I came back, figured out some last minute code to link the cart in our kickstarter project, got it to work, presented our site to the class, then the rest of the day was art class (a visual and conceptual primer before we dive into HTML/CSS next week).  I&rsquo;ve never painted on canvas before but it was therapeutic, fun, expressive, and reminded me of why since long ago I chased and fantasized about that crazy artist life so hard and never ever fully let go.  After, a few of us Fullstackers walked to Chinatown and ate soup dumplings at this place my cousin recommended (Shanghai Cafe).  It was good, and I caught the train, somehow found the way home, and Rob at school found my iphone (cause I left it at Fullstack).  Tomorrow is the weekend, an opportunity to continue working on our kickstarter project (cause our group is having so much fun we still on it like Voltron), or my own personal project, or the Rails Rumble project, and there&rsquo;s a hackathon to attend, and I will meditate, and do laundry, eat a great lunch, and do everything I&rsquo;ve ever wanted to do ever if I only had time, until the realization that it is 4pm on Sunday sets in &ndash; the weekend is over &ndash; and I become slightly sad at all the things I now &ldquo;have to do&rdquo; instead of &ldquo;want to do,&rdquo; then get over it, wonder where another week of my life went, then eventually freak out at how awesome and possible everything that ever existed ever was again because it&rsquo;s now next Friday afternoon/evening (aka Golden Hour).  Then again.  And again.  and Again.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s still great though.</p>

<p><img src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v416/yelofngr/senshot-2.png" title="i paint lion" alt="original lion" /></p>

<p><img src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v416/yelofngr/senshot-2.png" title="i paint lion" alt="i paint lion" /></p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[world on rails]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/18/day-number-24/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-18T10:25:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/18/day-number-24</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>Rails is making more sense (and losing its magic).  I am getting the sense (sixth) more &ndash; to know where to dig &ndash; controller, model, views, routes.  Working through this project, I feel I got a better grasp of what the controller and the model does and how to divide &ldquo;za bizness&rdquo; between the two.  I got a better idea of how the associations work and how to worm through those associations and methods to find the exact value you are looking for.  I would like to practice more model associations/method accessing in the future to really solidify the feel.</p>

<p>Working in a team of 4 this time was fun and a dream.  We used Trello as our hub strategy (strategery), and we&rsquo;d break, go off into the wilderness, forage for working code (delicious code mushrooms), come back, share our discoveries, then push (git push) the project forward.  I know it won&rsquo;t always be this easy, maybe we just hit a good flow this time, but it&rsquo;s nice to know that it can.  In the beginning, I personally felt that we were trying to install too many features right off the get-go (especially after reading &lsquo;Getting Real&rsquo; all Sunday, I&rsquo;d become a devoted acolyte), but we eventually threw everything into the Trello product backlog and found a way as a group to focus first on the essentials.  It also helped that there was soooo much work to be done that we kinda knew we&rsquo;d just be chewing and chewing, and however much we bit through, was gonna just be that.  Being at a buffet with a stapled stomach takes the pressure off.  I like group work.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[team sports]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/18/day-number-23/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-18T00:37:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/18/day-number-23</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>We is a team.  We make the circle.  We is I.T. Swenson, the finest purveyor of Swedish-made salmon-meat toothpaste tubes.  We also sell furniture (naturally.  we are Swedish).  Our delivery rates are bananasss.  Like, I mean, so low you&rsquo;re taking advantage of us.  We&rsquo;re still winning somehow, though.  We love pricing hacks.  Our pants are permanently-perfectly creased (perma-perf).  We own a ferry boat that we let normal people also ride on, if they have a receipt.  We&rsquo;ll let you ride though, just cause we like you.  Feel special, but not too special, because we also like everyone.  We only drive Bugattis.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[I only drive Bugattis]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/16/day-number-22/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-16T20:02:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/16/day-number-22</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>What a difference some sleep makes.  I&rsquo;m finally caught up on rest after the weekend.  It&rsquo;s Wednesday.  It&rsquo;s not even about having crazy weekends, it&rsquo;s about not working yourself to death(you&rsquo;ll always feel like you don&rsquo;t have enough time if you simply feel that way), then not blowing off steam recklessly (sleeping at 5am two nights in a row will really rock your sleep schedule).  It&rsquo;s about balance.  Knowing how to take time to pace and not work 14 days in a row (bad idea), then knowing how to go see friends but not stay out late to make up for working 14 days straight (bad idea + bad idea = just bad idea).</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been hearing this from various sources lately, and it&rsquo;s a good piece to keep around &ndash; &ldquo;It&rsquo;s a marathon, not a sprint.&rdquo;  It&rsquo;s going to take time for new concepts, a brand new way of thinking, a brand new way of looking at the world, to truly sink in.  This is probably gonna change the way your brain puts everything together, so be patient.  If you do find yourself in a mad scram up a 90deg slope, just know, this is kinda what it is supposed to be.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m progressing.  I&rsquo;m soaking it all up.  It&rsquo;s coming.  It&rsquo;s been a month really.  I&rsquo;m relearning America too (personal struggle).  Show up, show up, show up.  Show up, pace, keep fun, keep joy, and cruise.  Eye-of-the-storm.  Eezy peezy.</p>

<p>Today, we continued chopping up and rolling out like Navy Seals on this kickstarter project.  We scrum in Trello, then break, handle our parts, then git push, clear our commits, then group pull back down like we are sitting at some cotton spider-loom of interweb construction.  With guidance, we managed to install Stripe&rsquo;s credit-card payment API onto our page as checkout.  It&rsquo;s simple and barebones, but exciting.  Mostly because to test it, I keep paying myself lots of imaginary ducats and my customer count keeps climbing.  Soon I&rsquo;ll be rolling deep like 37signals and DHH, getting 10,000+ github commits, people flying me to talk about which Ruby gem is my favorite, which unicode symbol I prefer on my prompt during the Autumn Equinox, hipchatting honey-babies in my Bugatti, as I drip start-up ideas all over the place like a child discovering honey, money.</p>

<p>Man, it&rsquo;s a different world.</p>

<p><img src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v416/yelofngr/screenshot-2.png" title="keep paying me" alt="keep paying me" /></p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[vicissitudes]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/15/day-number-21/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-15T20:20:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/15/day-number-21</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>Day 2 of kickstarter/crowdtilt.  We break chunks.  We scrum with the best of them.  We are the scrummiest.  Sometimes you non-stop win, other times you tear your sweater on a splinter &ndash; it&rsquo;s all good, you&rsquo;re still in the game.  Today, tackled and cleared up (to a certain extent) more under-hood Rails voodoo.  Associations are like untangling really thin and long earphone cables.  Patience, man, patience.  You wanna hear the music, don&rsquo;t you?  Did you know all about these things Rails is doing behind your back?  Creating 11 methods just because you said &lsquo;has_many&rsquo;?  Hey.  Surprise on me.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s coming together, though.</p>

<p>Any progress is good progress.  And a whole bunch of other mantra type shit.  It&rsquo;s all true.</p>

<p>Until it&rsquo;s not true.</p>

<p>Our usual Fullstack Tuesday dinners was had yesterday when Andy, a freelance developer came by to share his vision of a trans-global life &ndash; free to work, free to be (which in his case is running marathons all over the world including Kenya and Alaska(?).  His current client wouldn&rsquo;t care if he was gone for 6mos on a beach in Thailand as long as his git pushes kept coming through and clean.  I&rsquo;m willing to stretch it to 1 or 2 yrs.  First, got to get the builder skills up though, wrestle some open source, get a few gems named after me and my body parts.</p>

<p>Late in the day, I invented an app that will aggregate people&rsquo;s grandmas and then farm them out to stranger&rsquo;s homes where they cook people really kickass home-meals for money.  Grandma Swap.  Or, maybe more like Grandma Pimp, huh.  Will the SPCA be mad at me?  I promise they&rsquo;re all free-range grandmas.  If anyone is interested in trusting me with your grandmas, let me know.  I&rsquo;m an old lady&rsquo;s dream.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[project based]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/15/day-number-20/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-15T01:23:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/15/day-number-20</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>A third of the program is now in the bag.  In another 2 weeks, we will be shifting to pure projects.  It&rsquo;s kind of unbelievable.  However much I&rsquo;ve learned at this point, I&rsquo;m not even sure &ndash; I&rsquo;m just used to the struggle.  Today, we began constructing our own version of kickstarter/crowdtilt.  It&rsquo;s a meaty one for sure.  Working through it will only solidify the Rails understanding deeper.  Javascript will come soon as well, and then, the world.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[run-down]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/11/day-number-19/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-11T00:44:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/11/day-number-19</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m excited about things.  Ideas, progress.  I finally cracked through a RSpec till all green completion alllmmost by myself earlier today.  Triumph.  Rails is becoming more sensible.  We have an evaluation tomorrow.  Too tired, can&rsquo;t read my many furious notes.  Study in the morning.  Also, note to self, no more 7-day continuous study/work weeks &ndash; Sunday must be an off-day.  Okay, friend.  Also, must eat lunch every day &ndash; skimming by on cereal is no bueno.  Check.  Got some inspirato from fellow classmate/comrade regarding project today.  Gonna run it by the pros (Dave &amp; Nim), flesh out more, and maybe it be hackable.  Exciting.  Reading book on start-up culture over weekend.  Looking forward to it.  Earlier today, we had a code-typing-speed relay competition.  Spice it up.  Macbook chicklet keys usually low-pro and smooth to touch, but not as fancy when your fingers shaking from nerves.  Werd.</p>

<p><img src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v416/yelofngr/image.jpg" title="Team anchors Finger(Michael)Phelps and the Bombay(Key)Banger going head-to-head for tears, glory, and coffee" alt="Team anchors Finger(Michael)Phelps and the Bombay(Key)Banger going head-to-head for tears, glory, and coffee" /></p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[cat claws]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/10/day-number-18/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-10T01:09:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/10/day-number-18</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>Cat claws be latching my jeans, like Rails latch me brain.  We worked on putting the StackWorld website room warp project onto pure Rails today, and it was a good chance to wrap our heads around the whole structure, MCV, behind-the-scenes voodoo, all that jazz.  I had my sleep and ate more of my bagel than I usually do, had toooo many cups of green tea, was amped, and driving, driven, and droven.  Head down, forking and porking, it wasn&rsquo;t easy, but it was doable.  Definitely doable.  It&rsquo;s always the little hiccups that get you.  Misspellings, effing misspellings.  Am I misspelling mispelings now? oh soh me-tta.  Mis-spellings will mess you up man.  And this whole Rails-so-smart-it-know-plurals! mess, will also mess you up.  Remember &ndash; models => singular.  Controller => plural.  This saves trouble, keeps nosebleed blood inside brain.  Tomorrow is coming.  Tomorrow will come soon.  I must sleep.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[day old]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/10/day-number-17/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-10T00:59:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/10/day-number-17</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p><img src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v416/yelofngr/screenshot-1.png" title="day late evernote 001" alt="day late evernote 001" /></p>

<p>I couldn&rsquo;t figure out the rails/ruby/git situation until today, so here&rsquo;s the evernote screenshot.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the link for easy clicking: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cMcEgOPza8A">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cMcEgOPza8A</a></p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[pieces]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/08/day-number-16/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-08T01:04:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/08/day-number-16</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>After a weekend, that didn&rsquo;t feel much like a weekend because it was spent catching up on pre-work and learning about Rails, Monday rolled on forth with more Rails.  I was kinda glad I stayed in and brushed up, and by brushed up, I mean learned for the first time, Rails, because we dove right into it today.  Sinatra &ndash; out.  Rails in.  Rails is crazy cause with 2 command line returns, there&rsquo;s this mass of folders and controllers, routes, models, html/css that&rsquo;s just blegghgh right there.  Kinda like how this morning I awoke to my friend&rsquo;s cat wailing and making caulking-gun sounds.  I open the door, and there it was.  All this vomit everywhere.  Hello, Ruby on Rails generate scaffold function!</p>

<p>Still working out the kinks, the connections, and my feelings towards this whole framework.  I went to a childhood friend&rsquo;s place for dinner and he asked me, so what does Rails do when you build a website?  Good question.  I just told him it&rsquo;s like some sort of glue that seeps in and makes things easier between html and SQL, and everything&hellip; um, yeah.  That&rsquo;s Rails!  Get&rsquo;s all up in there, you know?  Kinda like that cat vomit is all up inbetween the wood planks.  That&rsquo;s part of the house now.</p>

<p>Oh man, Rails, what have they been feeding you?</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[it's hard, but we walk anyway]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/05/day-number-15/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-05T17:40:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/05/day-number-15</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>I wish I had some great metaphor or anecdote that would move you right here, crumble the mountains and shake the shores, but I don&rsquo;t.  I just got reality in my pockets, and life in my veins.  And, it&rsquo;s gonna have to be enough.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s hard, but we walk anyway.</p>

<p>This is informed both by the current state of affairs in code-land, but also by my own personal affairs back home.  The bridge isn&rsquo;t hard to forge.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s hard, but we walk anyway.</p>

<p>Friday, we worked on crawlers to gank links off our Stackworld pages from the day before.  Gank, recursive; self-replicating viruses of gankdom.</p>

<p>Saturday, I&rsquo;m here again, but I&rsquo;m not really here.  I&rsquo;m giving it all I got in time, energy, and mind, but other things got my heart.  And, I think that&rsquo;s okay.  Not everything&rsquo;s a straight-line, even in immersive 3month programs.  Goals, achievements, careers, fancy/expensive pieces of paper, jobs, all these little applications, still need to be made available by the server of health, love, and life.  I&rsquo;m especially reminded of that today.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s hard, but we walk anyway.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s a drawing I made trying to understand things:</p>

<p><img src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v416/yelofngr/image1.jpg" title="Heroku/Sinatra/Ruby/Sqlite3 relationship tree" alt="Heroku/Sinatra/Ruby/Sqlite3 relationship tree" /></p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[sabbath]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/03/day-number-14/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-03T22:19:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/03/day-number-14</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>With the coming autumn/winter season, people are flipping out about colds/viruses/flus and the such, hand-sanitizer companies are padding their expense accounts in hand-sanitizer company-like ways like a company scavenger hunt in a landfill followed by a company picnic.  Free hand-sanitizer for all involved including family/friends, of course!  In my mind, companies and employees of said companies all joyously and single-mindedly pursue the seamless integration of their product into their lives &ndash; hence a hand-sanitizer company employee just CAN&rsquo;T WAIT to test the extent of hand-sanitizer power in their lives and really stick it to those germs!  Following this example, I will save my exposition on the valor and robustness of condom-company employees for another day when morale is truly low.  You simply won&rsquo;t believe what a couple hundredths of a millimeter of latex will embolden an otherwise sane human being to attempt.  For the company!</p>

<p>Sickness, illness, colds.  I see at them as life&rsquo;s breaks.  If your body can&rsquo;t fight off a common cold, it&rsquo;s probably because you are overextended.  We all work so hard, sometimes something outside of ourselves mercifully taps us on the shoulder, and puts the brakes on for us.  Colds, even the flu, they are more opportunities for rest than outside invaders that must be defeated.  The body is strong and knows what to do.  Trust it.  Rest it.</p>

<p>Today, started off as another high-aspiration day as we do at Fullstack Academy, but for some reason we caught a cold.  Well, the campus did &ndash; the internet went out.  For a tech house, wifi is the air in your nostrils.  Time to blow the nose, sip some soda, watch TV and sleep &ndash; we took it easy today.  I think once all of our internal meth-rock-chewing slave-drivers surrendered to the idea that we were not getting anything done until the internet was back on, we were able to let go of the pace; some of us even left the building, went outside, took a stroll, overlooked the water, stared off into nothing, lied down on the boardwalk.</p>

<p>Of course, it was easy to figure exactly when the internet was back on &ndash; silence, heads returned downward at a slight 78degrees &ndash; plugged in, dropped out &ndash; back in the machine.</p>

<p>We still managed to cover Ruby regular expressions, and discuss web crawling.  Tomorrow we construct scrapers, I am excited about these little script-robots we&rsquo;ll be getting a handle on.  The read-ups sound ever-so slightly suspect though &ndash; this is where hackers(as in trying to make code work) and hackers(as in breaking into code that&rsquo;s not theirs) begin to get some bridges.  I like it.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[fancy seeing u here]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/02/day-number-13/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-02T22:52:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/02/day-number-13</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>The Active Record/Sinatra/SQLite collabo.. wait, did we start it yesterday or fresh today?  Who knows anymore.  I just had to check my own blog, to write my own blog.  Head in a fog, log, bog, smog, brog.  Today was fun.  We made weird worlds, and I put chips and salsa everywhere, and David put guac, and Nimit hi-jacked my macbook like a Somali pirate and I&rsquo;m that new Tom Hanks movie where it&rsquo;s stressful and he grows a beard and keeps order over his seamen.  Surely persistence and the drive to discover is how you learn (so that&rsquo;s how you get good at things!).</p>

<p>Week 3 of the program, rolling along &ndash; thinking that we are already 25% of the way through the course, puts the fear in me like a lake of fire/gnashing of teeth next to the devil could never instill.  YOU ARE ALREADY &frac14; OF THE WAY THROUGH WITH YOUR WEB DEV IMMERSIVE SOON YOU WILL TAKE THE SKILLS YOU HAVE ACQUIRED FIND A JOB AND START WORKING WITH SAID SKILLS ON THE DAILY FOR MONEY.  This statement, is so fucking scary, it could be used in your favor to convert me to any religion/religions/causes/cults/sex-cults/porno-cage-dungeons of your heart&rsquo;s desire.  Yes, I will do porn if you just keep yelling that sentence at me.  I&rsquo;m so scared, yes, I&rsquo;m ready to shoot!!</p>

<p>In less scary news, or actually, rather debatable, check out what I made at school today mama!</p>

<p><a href="https://dry-tundra-6501.herokuapp.com/person/new">https://dry-tundra-6501.herokuapp.com/person/new</a></p>

<p>Come on in, have some chips n salsa in the foyer, kick up a shoe or two, pee in my double golden toilets (made of real gold, not that plated stuff), take a bounce or three in my double moon bounces, and check out some real meat in the dry-age-room/muscle dungeon.  But only if you dare.  Don&rsquo;t eat spaghetti squash in front of your keyboard while you explore these wormholes either, soldier.  Also, go ahead, put in your name (I&rsquo;ll never see it), create some rooms and add items to your heart&rsquo;s content (I will see these), and make some connections between those rooms to keep Wenson Stack World spicier than a mala pepper gone down the wrong throat path.</p>

<p>Don&rsquo;t be shy.  Here, to help things along, I&rsquo;ll tell/show you about myself.</p>

<p><img src="http://mayaday.files.wordpress.com/2010/03/funny-asian-face.jpg" title="JACKSON FROLIC" alt="Jackson Frolic" /></p>

<p>name:  Jackson Frolic <br>
description:  gum drops and jelly breams!<br><br></p>

<p>** breams are a type of fish like a snapper.  i kno how 2 type ohkay</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[day n nite]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/01/day-number-12/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-01T23:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/01/day-number-12</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>Today, we had our 3rd Fullstack Dinner, and it was pizza.  Grandma&rsquo;s pizza, Grandpa&rsquo;s pizza, White pizza, mushroom pizza (which no one touched inexplicably) &ndash; the pizza game be diversified.  The day was one with a good flow &ndash; we first learned about the internets.  The internets is busy, and it keeps passing stuff back and forth like basketball drills to keep us seeing things and un-revolty.  The US government was down today (effing ridiculous), but hey, it&rsquo;s fine when you can watch people do things on Brobible.com (mind sanitize).</p>

<iframe src="http://wensontsai.github.io//player.vimeo.com/video/14570497" width="500" height="375" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p> <p><a href="http://vimeo.com/14570497">Packet Flight: RickRoll @ 12X</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/carlosb">Carlos Bueno</a> on <a href="https://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p></p>

<p>Then we moved on to designing this multi-room portal site pulling in Sinatra, Rails(Active Record), SQL, and HTML/CSS which was pretty cool, cause it lets people come onto your site, and then create a room and name things.  Of course, the first room I named was the toilet, because every good space including a wormhole, needs a toilet (keep it hyperspace-clean, son!).  My butt cheeks be allergic to anything that&rsquo;s not gold even when I&rsquo;m space-dimensional-contiuum-irrespective-morphing/traveling.</p>

<p><img src="http://maison.trouvetout.ca/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/hong-kon-golden-toilet1.jpg" title="golden toilet" alt="golden toilet" /></p>

<p>I went back in time to fetch a 24k gold spouted butt-washer add-on with adjustable pressure/temperature controls.  Worth the risk of having to fight dinosaurs/aliens/zombies.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[munday]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/30/day-number-11/"/>
		<updated>2013-09-30T23:51:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/30/day-number-11</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s a bit of a toss, between life and the immersive.  No one said it would be easy.  No one said this.  And, certainly, no one promised that weekends would be rejuvenating.</p>

<p>Today&rsquo;s work was comprehendable enough.  We got to know the mystical black magic that is Active Record (AR) in Ruby on Rails.  It speaks a sort of yoda backwards SQL, and it does a bunch of weird things behind your back (well, not super weird, but certainly AR has a bit of the flair for the theatrical), oh, and did I mention, sir/madaam AR cares about your use of singles vs plural, even when it&rsquo;s only referencing your class objects as such for its own entertainment?  To not do so, would be uncivilized.</p>

<p>Oh, I&rsquo;m coming apart on a munday funday.  The week is a young-day.  Better keep strong.  Today, my pair-partner came down with a sickness, and now family-sized dispensers of Purell are on every desk in the house.  Keep the energy up, keep the health meters up, the mana and the mojo.  Rest, all you have to do is rest, and it&rsquo;ll be all right.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[death of pig-latin]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/28/day-number-10/"/>
		<updated>2013-09-28T16:18:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/28/day-number-10</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>I thought it would take me the next 5 years of my life, but with a shit-ton of help and explanation, failed thought process/approaches, hipchat support, sacrifice of a saturday, housecat jealousy, pure grudgery sprinkled on top, I re-wrote the code for the pig-latin testfirst.org problem, got it to work, and also understand it.</p>

<p>Arrays to strings to arrays to arrays to strings to goddamnit computer, why cant you just think the way I think, and we can be friends and share the same underpants?  You don&rsquo;t wear underpants.</p>

<p>Pig-Latin is dead!!</p>

<p>5 years of life has come back to me, and now I&rsquo;m thinking of skipping off to enjoy a Saturday night instead of working all the way through.  I am not a computer &ndash; just yet.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[grit]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/26/day-number-9/"/>
		<updated>2013-09-26T23:01:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/26/day-number-9</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>We wrapped up the Ruby/SQL query middle-layer build exercise today.  It was good.  Way envious of what my partner can just see, solve, and code.  While my brain pulls blanks, he&rsquo;s got gears turning, and with the gear-turning you got stuff to try.  I like trying stuff.  Running code, whether right or wrong, may be a distant cousin of slot machines.  Gimme more code for me nickel slots.</p>

<p>We then got into groups to present about classes vs instances, class methods vs instance methods.  They say teaching is the best way to learn.  To teach, you got to feel like you got it under wraps.  Then to bring someone outside of yourself to understanding, well that&rsquo;s a whole nother thing.</p>

<p>I believe in giving.</p>

<p>Not as some tax write-off, but as a human activity we all should be involved in.  To be honest, it doesn&rsquo;t even matter what you give.  It&rsquo;s just important to reach outside of yourself, help others, be connected &ndash; there&rsquo;s a true joy in it.</p>

<p>Information is definitely one of the easiest things to give.  But not necessarily one of the easiest to receive.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m feeling pretty lucky watching the teachers at Fullstack.  It turns on the lights in that teacher part of me I nurtured in Japan.  I would have stayed as late as possible or done about anything to help my students grow and understand.  Few rewards are better than being there to usher someone along and change their lives.  I get why in traditional Chinese society, teachers and intellectuals were the most respected social class.  I get why being a teacher in Japanese society pretty much means you are a public pillar of society and a parent to your students for life.</p>

<p>A good teacher will inevitably change the lives of their students.</p>

<p>To believe in someone when they had no faith, to shine a light where they knew not to look, a good teacher gives themselves &ndash; the student and teacher are one &ndash; their growth is your growth, their achievement, your achievement.  We all run on limited time in this life.  Time is our most precious resource.  How else can you feel but grateful for another who spends their minutes improving yours?</p>

<p>I feel lucky that we are the first class at Fullstack.  I know from my own experience, I was able to give the most to the very first graduating class I taught.  Routine and the tear of putting yourself out there over and over can wear even the best.  It&rsquo;s definitely better to be Taiwan than Korea **.</p>

<p>Thank you for the information and the guidance.  Thank you for your dedication, time, faith, support, and encouragement.  It is an inspiration.</p>

<p>Believe you me, I will hold up my end of the deal.</p>

<p>** When Japan was trying to put an empire together to compete with the &lsquo;civilized West&rsquo; (ironically out of a fear of being colonized themselves) they planned to make Taiwan their model first colony.  They pumped infrastructure into there, and although there was conflict, it&rsquo;s quite a stark contrast from when Japan tried to colonize Korea.  Taiwan still has a soft spot for Japan until this day, where as revenge on Japan has been a fire under Koreans for the past half century.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[are we human, or are we object]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/25/day-number-8/"/>
		<updated>2013-09-25T21:14:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/25/day-number-8</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>Today was pleasant.  We wrapped up the sqlite3 workshop we had begun.  I dig it, man.  Inner joins are just like crappy 80&rsquo;s arcade versions of mah-jong (ain&rsquo;t got nothing on the real tiles).  You match up pairs and they disappear.  You want the win? you match up the faces &ndash; pretty much for joins, you got to be as indirect as possible.  You match up two obviouses, just so you can get your in-obvious column.  I can appreciate the mystery and the behind-room-divider finesse.</p>

<p>After we got a handle on SQL commands, we dove back into Ruby, turning each table into a class object, and columns into attributes.  We were to build the middle layer for Ruby to interact with SQL &ndash; building a helper.</p>

<p>It was around then while working through some discrepancies that I came to realize how meta everything was getting.  It used to be just data, basic containers to keep that data, keys to access that data, but now we were dealing with objects.  Objects are only objects in so much as you can imagine a container in the paper of your mind.  We were beyond information you can scribble in a notebook, or wrap in neat curly braces.  Objects.  Are objects even real?  Do objects care if we feel pain?  The information, the words you had before, they&rsquo;re thrown into objects and turned into mere attributes.  Attributes of the object!  What is this &lsquo;object&rsquo;?  A blender for all things real?  How cold!  Your name, your tastes, they have meaning, personality &ndash; in a curly bracket, square bracket, parentheses, they are still themselves, just in a room.  But, in objects &ndash;  now, they were part of the machine.  Emotionless attributes now.  Accessed as so.  Mere markers, of what used to be.</p>

<p>And, right then and there, I had an existential breakdown.</p>

<p>Are we human, or are we object?</p>

<p>I mean, I&rsquo;m just a mere instance of the human class (think human factory).  I run methods like eat, walk, love, make_babies, make_poo, ponder_the_meaning_of_life, laugh, flirt, talk_shit.  I can make_the_world_a_better_place taking arguments like giving, or caring, or I can run methods steal, or murder(with_knife) or destroy(with_emotional_abuse).  And many more pre-programmed actions.</p>

<p>You ever done these online personality quizzes, or done the Myers-Briggs Type Indicator full-on with in-depth explanations regarding your tendencies, world perspective, thought processes, and intuitions?  I read one once just a few months prior that had me ALL FIGURED OUT.  Down to the most secret and fundamental of my instincts that I had put energy into developing, practice into trusting.</p>

<p>It was as if I was exactly where I was supposed to be, just that I, the one it was happening to, was the only one that didn&rsquo;t know.</p>

<p>I, me, whatever, exerting effort, right at the cusp of believing in progress, manuevering new directions, but everything I discovered, someone some thing already knew I would think, act, make sense this way, even as I was convinced I was doing everything of my own will and volition.  A simple text, I&rsquo;d never seen, already knew I would be trying to do so and predicted it.  It freaked me the fuck out.</p>

<p>Was it feasible that our destinies and fates could be so thinly veiled?  That the train and the track could glide ever so blatantly eye-to-eye?  How could it be, that life seems so original, so real, subjectively, yet be so easily uncovered and predictable?  I felt so ordinary, so cliche, so played-out, so kitsch.  Was I human, or was I object?  And, was I this way all along?  Why didn&rsquo;t anyone tell me?</p>

<p>Or,</p>

<p>was I supposed to feel this way, at this very point in time, as the fates and destinies and programming purposely pre-aligned &ndash; which was first, the chicken, the egg?  Could a chicken lay the very egg it is hatching out of simultaneously, just in time to lay another egg, which contains none other than itself?  What if the eggs were not chicken eggs at all, but duck eggs, with a purple-grey dead duck baby inside, and the Vietnamese friends you were drinking with told you to spoon lime juice with black pepper/chili paste onto its face and slurp &ndash; would it taste like cajun crawfish, even though it&rsquo;s neither cajun NOR crawfish??</p>

<p>How
fucking
predictable.</p>

<p>Hello World!
I&rsquo;d like you to meet someone:</p>

<p><img src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v416/yelofngr/screenshot.png" title="wenson bot" alt="wenson bot" /></p>

<p>ruby new_life.rb</p>

<p>::::::&hellip;&hellip;.. meep bloop blop bloop meep mrop breep.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?feature=player_embedded&v=RIZdjT1472Y
" target="_blank"><img src="http://img.youtube.com/vi/RIZdjT1472Y/0.jpg"
alt="are we human, or are we dancer" width="480" height="360" border="0" /></a></p>

<p>NoMethodError:
  undefined method &lsquo;DANCER&rsquo; for # _Rspec::Core::ExampleGroup::Nested_2::Nested_1:0x007ffda8042938>#./spec/requests/user_pages_spec.rb:9:in &lsquo;block (3 levels) in top(required&rsquo;</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[inspiration transfer]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/24/day-number-7/"/>
		<updated>2013-09-24T21:21:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/24/day-number-7</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>Rough.  That&rsquo;s all I can really say.  The going is rough.  It&rsquo;s full-on Rocky over here without the benefit of a Netflix summary telling you everything&rsquo;s gonna wrap up okay at the end of 1:45hrs run-time.  Driving rough.</p>

<p>We finished up the Rspec blackjack testing/coding endeavor today, didn&rsquo;t gain too much more ground on getting greens and drowning red failure statements.  Even after all was explained and done, I still felt drowny and heavy all up in the chest.  We then moved on to learning SQL.  Oh syntax, you are the worst ex-girlfriend of them all, I swear.</p>

<p>The crotch punches continued deep into dusk, with little to no tea-refill breaks (we were out of water tanks for the dispenser so I put some green tea in some seltzer water.  a bubbly gassy fail.) the abuse remained a flurry until our Fullstack Dinner ++ today where we were treated to a delicious and balanced meal from Digg Inn, loved ones and friends joined us, mostly I think, so they could lock in a mental/emotional picture for imagining where their significant other/loved ones are when they don&rsquo;t ever see them in person again until December.  It&rsquo;s busy up in here.</p>

<p>I was so tired and defeated, but soon summoned to life.  The two girls in the class beckoned me over to sit between them.  The other Taiwanese-American guy in the class mentored me about my life.  Apparently he was a movie producer on the side, all the while having his hands in the tech VC world.  Very interesting, and unexpected.  I spilled a bit of my past lives, and there we were in the middle of a long table, talking shop in that weird snooty entertainment industry way, making jokes about crafty and trail mix.  I always did love being on set.</p>

<p>He buckled down tough-love style, but I was listening.  His message? to focus down what exactly I wanted to get out of this experience &ndash; also, what I wanted to get out of the life I had remaining.  This intensity was really happening at the same table we ate bagels and cream cheese every morning, except with people all around watching the spectacle, but they didn&rsquo;t really exist anyway.  He gave me a lot to think about.</p>

<p>As people came and went, another group formed, and these two other students began talking about their dedication to working on personal projects.  Unexpected inspiration again.  I felt electrified to hear of them wishing this place had a shower so they could work around the clock to get stuff done.  We are already 10% of the way through the program, one said.  He&rsquo;s right.  Better get on it.</p>

<p>I will come up with a passion project of my own to spearhead the learning and networking and NASA fall-out transfer technologies and make me portfolio pretty and give me lots of fire when I talk about things I care about, get the toes and fingers all wet and sticky again in the cauldron of life and creativity and imagination and possibilities and yes.  I think there will be a capstone project before we finish anyways, and it will be fantastic to have a vehicle to push everything forth as I leave gravity behind and burn, burn, burn it up through the atmosphere.</p>

<p>The last few short and sudden hours have reminded me that eyes keep focused solely on the road, it miss the scenery.  The unseen benefits of a road trip are many.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[sock full of nickels]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/23/day-number-six/"/>
		<updated>2013-09-23T19:51:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/23/day-number-six</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>The dimensions of variables inside variables is increasing.  Today, we worked on Rspec testing/coding a program that pits a player vs a dealer in blackjack with the ability to write/load different strategies for game play.  It trucked along, the violence, and the bloodshed ~ they beat me over the head, they brutalize me!  Complaints of police brutality?  This is code brutality &ndash; growing pains still growing on day six.  But, the tolerance for it has grown as well.  It&rsquo;s become less personal.  The sailor begin to understand the waves.  I went home around the usual dismissal for one of the first times since the course begun.  Knowing your limits is vital for keeping on pace and riding the distance.  Get, git, get &lsquo;em tomorrow.  Power posing in bathrooms across the nation!</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
</feed>
