<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

	<title><![CDATA[Code Journey]]></title>
	<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
	<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/"/>
	<updated>2013-11-23T15:12:24-05:00</updated>
	<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/</id>
	<author>
		<name><![CDATA[Wenson Tsai]]></name>
		
	</author>
	<generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[T minus and it's on]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/11/23/day-number-41/"/>
		<updated>2013-11-23T12:33:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/11/23/day-number-41</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>There is literally 2 weeks left of Fullstack Academy.  Literally.</p>

<p>Thinking about it makes me bittersweet.  Even though a ton has happened, in a short amount of time &ndash; yet at the same time, it feels like it&rsquo;s been such a long time coming, a long road &ndash; man, we were just getting started, and now we gotta leave the nest.</p>

<p>Two weeks.</p>

<ul>
<li>Recruitment activities commence now</li>
<li>Start new demo project to sharpen Backbone.js skills and get heavy on the backend</li>
<li>Wrap up pretty the Escapergram project (my idea of an alternate universe escape for picture-lovers through the day, where at any time you could take a mini-vacation and see what was going on in another part of the world.  It pulls feed from the Instagram API, mapping from the Google maps API, and uses d3.js on the landing page).</li>
</ul>


<p>Yesterday, while doing our Friday demos, someone had the brilliant idea to live-post pictures of me demo-ing into the feed at the Fullstack latitude and longitude (within 5000 meter radius).  It&rsquo;d been a slow-brain day &ndash; I was just talking through the work I had added, but this shook me awake.  Interacting with the crowd is a must &ndash; that&rsquo;s where the fun is.</p>

<p>Waiting and manually refreshing the page, some photos might a slipped through (sadness).  But as a result, now Escapergrams got AJAX auto-refresh (every 10 secs).  Escape into the now to your heart&rsquo;s content, people!</p>

<p><a href="http://escapergram.herokuapp.com">escaperGRAM</a></p>

<p><img src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v416/yelofngr/IMG_4423.png" title="live-demo" alt="live-demo" /></p>

<p><img src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v416/yelofngr/IMG_4422.png" title="escapergrammm" alt="escapergrammm" /></p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[hackworld]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/11/17/day-number-40/"/>
		<updated>2013-11-17T10:46:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/11/17/day-number-40</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>The New York Times Hackathon was a great experience.  I&rsquo;m super glad I went.  Just 2 days prior, I was about to not go, but David posed the question &ndash; &ldquo;What&rsquo;s your excuse?&rdquo;</p>

<p>&ldquo;Err, I don&rsquo;t have a team,&rdquo; I replied.</p>

<p>&ldquo;Make one.&rdquo;</p>

<p>Off to work &ndash; I committed myself to figuring out an idea before lunchtime that day.  After flipping through the sponsor API&rsquo;s, I hit on something fun.  What if we could use the NY Public Library&rsquo;s (sponsor) <a href="http://menus.nypl.org/">Menu API</a> with another API to find places to eat obscure dishes from the 1800&rsquo;s?  Fortunately, this was received well by other students looking to participate, and there you go, I had a team.</p>

<p>The morning of, me and <a href="http://hjbuchanan.github.io/">Hanj</a> were the first people there.  After getting in, then averting a near catastrophe (a team-member forgot his laptop at a bar the night before, possibly losing his entire capstone project), Rob, Eric, Jules, and I got to work on putting together the Menu app.  As per discussions the night before, Jules (veteran hackathon champ) recommended we simply use d3 to graph out the most popular items over decades (we were doing this compromise because there wouldn&rsquo;t be enough time for my original idea I assumed).</p>

<p>A strange thing happend around 3pm, just 5 hours before we were to decide whether we would demo or not.  We found that Jules&#8217; idea to data visualize was already a feature on the NYPL Menu site, AND it looked good hahaha.  Again I suggested we try my original idea.  It was at this point that both Jules and Hanj admitted, they didn&rsquo;t realize that was what I was going for, and that having an app to find places to eat popular dishes from the 1800&rsquo;s is &lsquo;an even better more fun idea!&rsquo;  To quote from fellow student/fashion hawk <a href="http://istevenson.github.io/">Imon</a> &ndash; &ldquo;Well, DUHHHHHHHHH HH H.. .&rdquo;  Where these cats been??</p>

<p>Just like that, we reorganized and went back into our rabbit holes.  Around 7pm, Rob had figured out timeline.js, and my map functionalities came in for a landing in Eric&rsquo;s frontend and Jules&#8217; backend.</p>

<p>Then we presented.  And we watched other people present.  Our fellow Fullstackers (we ended having 3 separate teams) took the People&rsquo;s Choice Award with their &ldquo;Right-wingify the NY Times&rdquo; hack, that got people in the crowd so worked up I saw people crying from laughter.</p>

<p>That Brookyln Lager around 10pm never tasted so good.</p>

<p>Lessons learned:  Being my first hackathon experience, I wasn&rsquo;t sure what to expect, but observing, participating, and achieving goals, I felt that all the projects that day were within our capabilities.  In fact, if I may say so (and I realize this is me saying so about our own project), our Menu app was within the top 87th percentile of interesting works.  And, that was with burning half the day just trying to find our direction!</p>

<p>All in all, I recommend if you have a chance, to attend hackathons, generate ideas, see them come to life, meet some people, eat some food, and most importantly, get a handle on some swaggggg</p>

<p><img src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v416/yelofngr/IMG_4428.jpg" title="swagggg" alt="swagggg" /></p>

<p><img src="https://gs1.wac.edgecastcdn.net/8019B6/data.tumblr.com/4cfd608cbaca71f4b1b043ac8fde47e2/tumblr_mwef97PbDQ1ryra09o2_1280.jpg" title="early view" alt="early view" /></p>

<p><img src="https://gs1.wac.edgecastcdn.net/8019B6/data.tumblr.com/7d02addc16ab240d50d87e87a19bae42/tumblr_mwef97PbDQ1ryra09o3_1280.jpg" title="off to races" alt="off to races" /></p>

<p><img src="https://gs1.wac.edgecastcdn.net/8019B6/data.tumblr.com/df7ff91cf714c123d7081e0188ad4a49/tumblr_mwef97PbDQ1ryra09o4_1280.jpg" title="right-wingify ruling things" alt="right-wingify ruling things" /></p>

<p><img src="https://gs1.wac.edgecastcdn.net/8019B6/data.tumblr.com/f4878bd383ec76a3045ae3b27830a2ba/tumblr_mwef97PbDQ1ryra09o5_1280.jpg" title="team yes" alt="team yes" /></p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[innit]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/11/15/day-number-35/"/>
		<updated>2013-11-15T09:57:00-05:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/11/15/day-number-35</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been away.  I&rsquo;ll tell you why.  I was feeling crushed by the crush of the self-crush.  Learning the full stack had become the beast that I could never feed enough &ndash; not enough energy, study, effort, time, weekends, or nights &ndash; the beast had become a burden.  Advice of the head is hard to seep in the heart somehow, the membrane is pro- or anti- lipids I can&rsquo;t remember which one.  I realized the importance of not grinding your wheels and rails to a pulp &ndash; even choo-choos have limits &ndash; yet, there I was gunning like some 16-yr old rodeo bullrider with everything to prove and nothing to lose, all burn all the time.</p>

<p>I got 4 days away &ndash; I was determined to work during those 4 days, but as soon as I entered back into the lazy obese air of my place of birth, sitting in the oppressive quiet of my mother&rsquo;s house, backbone.js was gone.  Backbone.js couldn&rsquo;t be further away &ndash; iterm and sublime had no place in my plane of reality anymore.  It was just a few days, but I feel more grounded and grasping of a perspective on everything that is going on again.  Paradigm shifts are a must.  Rest is a must.</p>

<p>Here are some bullet points organized in no particular theme, purpose, nor order:</p>

<ul>
<li><p>about 2 weeks ago, Emily from MongoDB came to speak to us, and for the first time in my life I felt aroused about a database</p></li>
<li><p>my endurance has increased &ndash; I can now google search about something I know nothing about over and over for longer periods of time with less cop-out</p></li>
<li><p>I work better with earplugs in and music on</p></li>
<li><p>New York Times Hackathon this weekend !</p></li>
<li><p>I like capstone-project phase and the analog Trello system we got going in the classroom on a plane of glass.  Lewis and Clark up in the digital sphere with only the occasional courier dispatch.</p></li>
<li><p>Going home at 9pm no matter if I&rsquo;m feeling energetic or not is a life-saver must law</p></li>
<li><p>It&rsquo;s all gonna get done &ndash; it just will.  No matter how many hours you put in or kill/sacrifice yourself for the work &ndash; it&rsquo;ll get done somehow.  Often in the end, it doesn&rsquo;t even matter.  A friend wiser than me who&rsquo;s lived through it told me.</p></li>
<li><p>Coding remains a subclass that inherits from the class of life.  Never forget it.</p></li>
<li><p>Charlotte yoga is a lifesaver.  Can she do Rails tutorials in her soothing voice?  Breathe in through the nostrils, Movies has_many Actors.  Now breathe out through the mouth &ndash; AHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHhhh h h</p></li>
<li><p>4 weeks left.  Let&rsquo;s have some f*cking fun.</p></li>
</ul>

]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[come together]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/11/01/day-number-30/"/>
		<updated>2013-11-01T09:39:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/11/01/day-number-30</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>I am excited that we are nearing the end of the stack.  There&rsquo;s lots of things I would love to have time to go back and work on.  I feel like I got the &ldquo;Europe in 3 days!&rdquo; tour.  I wanna go back, get lost on some old cobbled backstreets, chill out for an hour at a cafe, and really understand why French people get so uppity when you speak to them in English.</p>

<p>I am more and more convinced that hacking is definitely a DO-type endeavor.  Tomorrow I will begin to work on implementing a site that can link up various video screens, so people can play music together, attend a concert, a talk, or other social event.  I&rsquo;m werking to twerk the angles to see how it can be more of a social experiment &ndash; a platform free for the people to use and experiment with.  Teach me a thing or three, please.  I am imagining like your own Ticketmaster, your own Madison Square Garden.  A virtual concert hall/theatre/lecture space for selling tickets to whatever you can, whatever your followers love for you to share.  First things first though, just to get 3 screens to show up, and be able to throw that into a room.  Tiny step.  Long journey.</p>

<p>Front-end vs. back-end:  Front-end is exciting.  Back-end is necessary &ndash; it&rsquo;s solid, got fortitude, but no one notices the trunk of trees (unless there&rsquo;s a problem).  People drive upstate to watch leaves change though.  I am interested in getting more into UI/UX.</p>

<!-- The backbone.js presentation yesterday was blowing way over my head.

I'm pissed at Ajax right now.

The amalgamation of rails/activerecord/sql/ruby/mvc <=> erb/html <=> jQuery/ajax/javascript all on one page with all their objects and &#8220;.&#8220;&#8216;s kinda ravages my brain.  Can javascript pointers point to ruby objects that point to sql objects, or are javascript and ruby/rails object pointers more like two rivers that never intersect?  Or, do they intersect through the sql database? &#8211;>

]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[dribble, dunk, triangle offense]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/22/day-number-27/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-22T23:14:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/22/day-number-27</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>Michael Nutt, co-founder and CTO of Moveable Ink (<a href="https://moveableink.com">https://moveableink.com</a>) rolled through to drop some knowledge and experience tonight for Fullstack talk/dinner.  He came up with the idea for Moveable Ink on a Friday, coded a rough through the weekend, worked with no revenue for a year, but it took off and it&rsquo;s been going places ever since.  Also, Michael beat out 400 developers in the Hacking Education contest which encourages the public to make discoveries and build apps to improve education in America.  Pretty cool stuff.  Then Stephen Colbert awarded him the most American-y trophy ever, and he got to sit in the chair and the set of the Colbert Report (<a href="http://www.donorschoose.org/blog/2011/07/25/stephen-colbert-anoints-big-winner/">http://www.donorschoose.org/blog/2011/07/25/stephen-colbert-anoints-big-winner/</a>).</p>

<p>Michael was the guy who came over and helped us get our lego robot to work that fateful first Fullstack Friday eons ago &ndash; I had no idea he was such a start-up kingpin, tech and dev wizard &ndash; he&rsquo;s the nicest, most approachable guy.  Not to say talented, hard-working, and successful people are assholes &ndash; I just didn&rsquo;t know he had so many other important things to be doing instead of playing legos!</p>

<p>Today he spoke to us about scaling your business once it begins to take off, giving us insights on the app and database side of things.  It was a bit over my head, but really nice to hear.  Afterwards, a fellow student seemed a bit bewildered as well and felt lost.</p>

<p>I got these thoughts right then though, that one day we would be there.  Like, it&rsquo;s overwhelming now, because we&rsquo;re still trying to work out the basics, and they&rsquo;re talking high-level strategy.  You can&rsquo;t weave the defense, spin and glide, before you get your dribble down.  But once you got it like second nature, then you can focus on court vision, creativity, jerk and flow like a painting.  And, once you got that down, you can practice true inter-dependence and lead a team of 11 to victory.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;ll get there, I told him.  We&rsquo;ll get there.  It might not be on our plate right now, but it&rsquo;s on the table.  It&rsquo;s on the spread.  We&rsquo;ll get there.  Bring on the stories, the glory, the pain, the losses, the wins.  I like feeling like I can be in the game.  I like knowing I can be there.  Call my name so I may turn my head and see what tasty-goodness is available.  Point it out so I may smell it, dream, plot, werk and twerk.  Put notice on, so I may figure out how to get it on my plate because I&rsquo;m hungry.</p>

<p><img src="http://www.donorschoose.org/images/misc/hackinged/eagle500.jpg" title="BIG WINNER" alt="BIG WINNER" /></p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[brontosaurus bumps 'n stegosaurus stumps]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/22/day-number-26/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-22T00:35:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/22/day-number-26</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>One in, one out.  One on, one off.  Rejuved and burnt.  Crispy and lispy.  I say, Makuna-matata.  That&rsquo;s not even right, cause it&rsquo;s Hakuna-matata.  It&rsquo;s okay.  Today, we delved into HTML/CSS, played around a little with tings tings and tings &ndash; here&rsquo;s what I had at the end of the day.  Click on me tiger face!!</p>

<p><a href="http://snackybitties.tumblr.com/">http://snackybitties.tumblr.com/</a></p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[joy life beauty youth]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/19/day-number-25/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/19/day-number-25</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>The ebb and flow of intense emotions and experiences takes me up and leaves me at sea.  The sight of land is a luxury no one can expect &ndash; the rising and setting sun will simply have to do.  My friend, they talk about connecting the dots only in hindsight.  It&rsquo;ll all make sense then, like some tiny islands, when you hop lead you to the main piece, the big show, the motherland.  They talk about fumbling forth, fingers grasp fistfuls of darkness.  They, talk about many things.  When you live, the voices have nowhere to go, or maybe they are close, but your ears cannot process them as the wind rushes by and through your body, a just cracked window in a car makes an epic soundtrack &ndash; living a bit reckless is better than thinking cautious riding pine &ndash; at least I say.  And through it all, through this all, that&rsquo;s what I still say.  Bold.  I know.  Self-assured.  Cocksure.  Sure.  I feel young, and all things possible.  The grim and the grime of lesser times cannot hold on much longer.  It just can&rsquo;t.  And then on and on, it&rsquo;ll go.  To the next adventure lined up to see.</p>

<p>Today, was great.</p>

<p>Sometimes, people are scared to say shit is great.  They fear that maybe, it actually doesn&rsquo;t qualify as great.  Perhaps people around them will think they have shit standards, because what they proclaimed publicly as GREAT, was actually SHIT.  They cast doubt to say so also because, maybe, they think, the amounts of greats we have is limited, and if you keep having GREATs, then all the shit days leftover will come tumbling down and crush your spine, making you a paralyzed shitty cyborg living a life that&rsquo;s worse than death itself, that&rsquo;s why you always say shit is mediocre!  Just alright.  At best, meh!  Although, secretly inside, it was kinda really fucking good man, and you know it.  Shhh, don&rsquo;t let the fates know, or else they&rsquo;ll start distributing strife to balance the scales!  This is not the justice we seek.  Let the fates do what it do.  Your job is to be great, to experience as many great moments as you possibly can, to feel great as much as you possibly can.</p>

<p>Today, I was treated to a tour of WeWork offices today, dynamic, electric, packed with dream-chasers, start-ups, boutique operations, artists, fashionistas, free beer, free arcades, lots of glass with marker scribble, 30th floor New York views, and conference call phone booths.  Then, I had fish friday (king fish at Veronica&rsquo;s Kitchen food truck (the red sannnper is better)).  Then, I came back, figured out some last minute code to link the cart in our kickstarter project, got it to work, presented our site to the class, then the rest of the day was art class (a visual and conceptual primer before we dive into HTML/CSS next week).  I&rsquo;ve never painted on canvas before but it was therapeutic, fun, expressive, and reminded me of why since long ago I chased and fantasized about that crazy artist life so hard and never ever fully let go.  After, a few of us Fullstackers walked to Chinatown and ate soup dumplings at this place my cousin recommended (Shanghai Cafe).  It was good, and I caught the train, somehow found the way home, and Rob at school found my iphone (cause I left it at Fullstack).  Tomorrow is the weekend, an opportunity to continue working on our kickstarter project (cause our group is having so much fun we still on it like Voltron), or my own personal project, or the Rails Rumble project, and there&rsquo;s a hackathon to attend, and I will meditate, and do laundry, eat a great lunch, and do everything I&rsquo;ve ever wanted to do ever if I only had time, until the realization that it is 4pm on Sunday sets in &ndash; the weekend is over &ndash; and I become slightly sad at all the things I now &ldquo;have to do&rdquo; instead of &ldquo;want to do,&rdquo; then get over it, wonder where another week of my life went, then eventually freak out at how awesome and possible everything that ever existed ever was again because it&rsquo;s now next Friday afternoon/evening (aka Golden Hour).  Then again.  And again.  and Again.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s still great though.</p>

<p><img src="https://gs1.wac.edgecastcdn.net/8019B6/data.tumblr.com/22c5ce3433d25452b15c05270dc7ac85/tumblr_mv1yppqWRz1ryra09o1_1280.jpg" title="artists at work" alt="artists at work" /></p>

<p><img src="https://gs1.wac.edgecastcdn.net/8019B6/data.tumblr.com/581d6b91e581533e375261abd5b08732/tumblr_mv1yppqWRz1ryra09o2_1280.jpg" title="I paint lion" alt="I paint lion" /></p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[world on rails]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/18/day-number-24/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-18T10:25:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/18/day-number-24</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>Rails is making more sense (and losing its magic).  I am getting the sense (sixth) more &ndash; to know where to dig &ndash; controller, model, views, routes.  Working through this project, I feel I got a better grasp of what the controller and the model does and how to divide &ldquo;za bizness&rdquo; between the two.  I got a better idea of how the associations work and how to worm through those associations and methods to find the exact value you are looking for.  I would like to practice more model associations/method accessing in the future to really solidify the feel.</p>

<p>Working in a team of 4 this time was fun and a dream.  We used Trello as our hub strategy (strategery), and we&rsquo;d break, go off into the wilderness, forage for working code (delicious code mushrooms), come back, share our discoveries, then push (git push) the project forward.  I know it won&rsquo;t always be this easy, maybe we just hit a good flow this time, but it&rsquo;s nice to know that it can.  In the beginning, I personally felt that we were trying to install too many features right off the get-go (especially after reading &lsquo;Getting Real&rsquo; all Sunday, I&rsquo;d become a devoted acolyte), but we eventually threw everything into the Trello product backlog and found a way as a group to focus first on the essentials.  It also helped that there was soooo much work to be done that we kinda knew we&rsquo;d just be chewing and chewing, and however much we bit through, was gonna just be that.  Being at a buffet with a stapled stomach takes the pressure off.  I like group work.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[team sports]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/18/day-number-23/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-18T00:37:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/18/day-number-23</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>We is a team.  We make the circle.  We is I.T. Swenson, the finest purveyor of Swedish-made salmon-meat toothpaste tubes.  We also sell furniture (naturally.  we are Swedish).  Our delivery rates are bananasss.  Like, I mean, so low you&rsquo;re taking advantage of us.  We&rsquo;re still winning somehow, though.  We love pricing hacks.  Our pants are permanently-perfectly creased (perma-perf).  We own a ferry boat that we let normal people also ride on, if they have a receipt.  We&rsquo;ll let you ride though, just cause we like you.  Feel special, but not too special, because we also like everyone.  We only drive Bugattis.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[I only drive Bugattis]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/16/day-number-22/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-16T20:02:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/16/day-number-22</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>What a difference some sleep makes.  I&rsquo;m finally caught up on rest after the weekend.  It&rsquo;s Wednesday.  It&rsquo;s not even about having crazy weekends, it&rsquo;s about not working yourself to death(you&rsquo;ll always feel like you don&rsquo;t have enough time if you simply feel that way), then not blowing off steam recklessly (sleeping at 5am two nights in a row will really rock your sleep schedule).  It&rsquo;s about balance.  Knowing how to take time to pace and not work 14 days in a row (bad idea), then knowing how to go see friends but not stay out late to make up for working 14 days straight (bad idea + bad idea = just bad idea).</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ve been hearing this from various sources lately, and it&rsquo;s a good piece to keep around &ndash; &ldquo;It&rsquo;s a marathon, not a sprint.&rdquo;  It&rsquo;s going to take time for new concepts, a brand new way of thinking, a brand new way of looking at the world, to truly sink in.  This is probably gonna change the way your brain puts everything together, so be patient.  If you do find yourself in a mad scram up a 90deg slope, just know, this is kinda what it is supposed to be.</p>

<p>I&rsquo;m progressing.  I&rsquo;m soaking it all up.  It&rsquo;s coming.  It&rsquo;s been a month really.  I&rsquo;m relearning America too (personal struggle).  Show up, show up, show up.  Show up, pace, keep fun, keep joy, and cruise.  Eye-of-the-storm.  Eezy peezy.</p>

<p>Today, we continued chopping up and rolling out like Navy Seals on this kickstarter project.  We scrum in Trello, then break, handle our parts, then git push, clear our commits, then group pull back down like we are sitting at some cotton spider-loom of interweb construction.  With guidance, we managed to install Stripe&rsquo;s credit-card payment API onto our page as checkout.  It&rsquo;s simple and barebones, but exciting.  Mostly because to test it, I keep paying myself lots of imaginary ducats and my customer count keeps climbing.  Soon I&rsquo;ll be rolling deep like 37signals and DHH, getting 10,000+ github commits, people flying me to talk about which Ruby gem is my favorite, which unicode symbol I prefer on my prompt during the Autumn Equinox, hipchatting honey-babies in my Bugatti, as I drip start-up ideas all over the place like a child discovering honey, money.</p>

<p>Man, it&rsquo;s a different world.</p>

<p><img src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v416/yelofngr/screenshot-2.png" title="keep paying me" alt="keep paying me" /></p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[vicissitudes]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/15/day-number-21/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-15T20:20:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/15/day-number-21</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>Day 2 of kickstarter/crowdtilt.  We break chunks.  We scrum with the best of them.  We are the scrummiest.  Sometimes you non-stop win, other times you tear your sweater on a splinter &ndash; it&rsquo;s all good, you&rsquo;re still in the game.  Today, tackled and cleared up (to a certain extent) more under-hood Rails voodoo.  Associations are like untangling really thin and long earphone cables.  Patience, man, patience.  You wanna hear the music, don&rsquo;t you?  Did you know all about these things Rails is doing behind your back?  Creating 11 methods just because you said &lsquo;has_many&rsquo;?  Hey.  Surprise on me.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s coming together, though.</p>

<p>Any progress is good progress.  And a whole bunch of other mantra type shit.  It&rsquo;s all true.</p>

<p>Until it&rsquo;s not true.</p>

<p>Our usual Fullstack Tuesday dinners was had yesterday when Andy, a freelance developer came by to share his vision of a trans-global life &ndash; free to work, free to be (which in his case is running marathons all over the world including Kenya and Alaska(?).  His current client wouldn&rsquo;t care if he was gone for 6mos on a beach in Thailand as long as his git pushes kept coming through and clean.  I&rsquo;m willing to stretch it to 1 or 2 yrs.  First, got to get the builder skills up though, wrestle some open source, get a few gems named after me and my body parts.</p>

<p>Late in the day, I invented an app that will aggregate people&rsquo;s grandmas and then farm them out to stranger&rsquo;s homes where they cook people really kickass home-meals for money.  Grandma Swap.  Or, maybe more like Grandma Pimp, huh.  Will the SPCA be mad at me?  I promise they&rsquo;re all free-range grandmas.  If anyone is interested in trusting me with your grandmas, let me know.  I&rsquo;m an old lady&rsquo;s dream.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[project based]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/15/day-number-20/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-15T01:23:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/15/day-number-20</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>A third of the program is now in the bag.  In another 2 weeks, we will be shifting to pure projects.  It&rsquo;s kind of unbelievable.  However much I&rsquo;ve learned at this point, I&rsquo;m not even sure &ndash; I&rsquo;m just used to the struggle.  Today, we began constructing our own version of kickstarter/crowdtilt.  It&rsquo;s a meaty one for sure.  Working through it will only solidify the Rails understanding deeper.  Javascript will come soon as well, and then, the world.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[run-down]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/11/day-number-19/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-11T00:44:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/11/day-number-19</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m excited about things.  Ideas, progress.  I finally cracked through a RSpec till all green completion alllmmost by myself earlier today.  Triumph.  Rails is becoming more sensible.  We have an evaluation tomorrow.  Too tired, can&rsquo;t read my many furious notes.  Study in the morning.  Also, note to self, no more 7-day continuous study/work weeks &ndash; Sunday must be an off-day.  Okay, friend.  Also, must eat lunch every day &ndash; skimming by on cereal is no bueno.  Check.  Got some inspirato from fellow classmate/comrade regarding project today.  Gonna run it by the pros (Dave &amp; Nim), flesh out more, and maybe it be hackable.  Exciting.  Reading book on start-up culture over weekend.  Looking forward to it.  Earlier today, we had a code-typing-speed relay competition.  Spice it up.  Macbook chicklet keys usually low-pro and smooth to touch, but not as fancy when your fingers shaking from nerves.  Werd.</p>

<p><img src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v416/yelofngr/image.jpg" title="Team anchors Finger(Michael)Phelps and the Bombay(Key)Banger going head-to-head for tears, glory, and coffee" alt="Team anchors Finger(Michael)Phelps and the Bombay(Key)Banger going head-to-head for tears, glory, and coffee" /></p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[cat claws]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/10/day-number-18/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-10T01:09:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/10/day-number-18</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>Cat claws be latching my jeans, like Rails latch me brain.  We worked on putting the StackWorld website room warp project onto pure Rails today, and it was a good chance to wrap our heads around the whole structure, MCV, behind-the-scenes voodoo, all that jazz.  I had my sleep and ate more of my bagel than I usually do, had toooo many cups of green tea, was amped, and driving, driven, and droven.  Head down, forking and porking, it wasn&rsquo;t easy, but it was doable.  Definitely doable.  It&rsquo;s always the little hiccups that get you.  Misspellings, effing misspellings.  Am I misspelling mispelings now? oh soh me-tta.  Mis-spellings will mess you up man.  And this whole Rails-so-smart-it-know-plurals! mess, will also mess you up.  Remember &ndash; models => singular.  Controller => plural.  This saves trouble, keeps nosebleed blood inside brain.  Tomorrow is coming.  Tomorrow will come soon.  I must sleep.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[day old]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/10/day-number-17/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-10T00:59:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/10/day-number-17</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p><img src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v416/yelofngr/screenshot-1.png" title="day late evernote 001" alt="day late evernote 001" /></p>

<p>I couldn&rsquo;t figure out the rails/ruby/git situation until today, so here&rsquo;s the evernote screenshot.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s the link for easy clicking: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cMcEgOPza8A">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=cMcEgOPza8A</a></p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[it's hard, but we walk anyway]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/05/day-number-15/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-05T17:40:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/05/day-number-15</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>I wish I had some great metaphor or anecdote that would move you right here, crumble the mountains and shake the shores, but I don&rsquo;t.  I just got reality in my pockets, and life in my veins.  And, it&rsquo;s gonna have to be enough.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s hard, but we walk anyway.</p>

<p>This is informed both by the current state of affairs in code-land, but also by my own personal affairs back home.  The bridge isn&rsquo;t hard to forge.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s hard, but we walk anyway.</p>

<p>Friday, we worked on crawlers to gank links off our Stackworld pages from the day before.  Gank, recursive; self-replicating viruses of gankdom.</p>

<p>Saturday, I&rsquo;m here again, but I&rsquo;m not really here.  I&rsquo;m giving it all I got in time, energy, and mind, but other things got my heart.  And, I think that&rsquo;s okay.  Not everything&rsquo;s a straight-line, even in immersive 3month programs.  Goals, achievements, careers, fancy/expensive pieces of paper, jobs, all these little applications, still need to be made available by the server of health, love, and life.  I&rsquo;m especially reminded of that today.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s hard, but we walk anyway.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s a drawing I made trying to understand things:</p>

<p><img src="http://img.photobucket.com/albums/v416/yelofngr/image1.jpg" title="Heroku/Sinatra/Ruby/Sqlite3 relationship tree" alt="Heroku/Sinatra/Ruby/Sqlite3 relationship tree" /></p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[sabbath]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/03/day-number-14/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-03T22:19:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/03/day-number-14</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>With the coming autumn/winter season, people are flipping out about colds/viruses/flus and the such, hand-sanitizer companies are padding their expense accounts in hand-sanitizer company-like ways like a company scavenger hunt in a landfill followed by a company picnic.  Free hand-sanitizer for all involved including family/friends, of course!  In my mind, companies and employees of said companies all joyously and single-mindedly pursue the seamless integration of their product into their lives &ndash; hence a hand-sanitizer company employee just CAN&rsquo;T WAIT to test the extent of hand-sanitizer power in their lives and really stick it to those germs!  Following this example, I will save my exposition on the valor and robustness of condom-company employees for another day when morale is truly low.  You simply won&rsquo;t believe what a couple hundredths of a millimeter of latex will embolden an otherwise sane human being to attempt.  For the company!</p>

<p>Sickness, illness, colds.  I see at them as life&rsquo;s breaks.  If your body can&rsquo;t fight off a common cold, it&rsquo;s probably because you are overextended.  We all work so hard, sometimes something outside of ourselves mercifully taps us on the shoulder, and puts the brakes on for us.  Colds, even the flu, they are more opportunities for rest than outside invaders that must be defeated.  The body is strong and knows what to do.  Trust it.  Rest it.</p>

<p>Today, started off as another high-aspiration day as we do at Fullstack Academy, but for some reason we caught a cold.  Well, the campus did &ndash; the internet went out.  For a tech house, wifi is the air in your nostrils.  Time to blow the nose, sip some soda, watch TV and sleep &ndash; we took it easy today.  I think once all of our internal meth-rock-chewing slave-drivers surrendered to the idea that we were not getting anything done until the internet was back on, we were able to let go of the pace; some of us even left the building, went outside, took a stroll, overlooked the water, stared off into nothing, lied down on the boardwalk.</p>

<p>Of course, it was easy to figure exactly when the internet was back on &ndash; silence, heads returned downward at a slight 78degrees &ndash; plugged in, dropped out &ndash; back in the machine.</p>

<p>We still managed to cover Ruby regular expressions, and discuss web crawling.  Tomorrow we construct scrapers, I am excited about these little script-robots we&rsquo;ll be getting a handle on.  The read-ups sound ever-so slightly suspect though &ndash; this is where hackers(as in trying to make code work) and hackers(as in breaking into code that&rsquo;s not theirs) begin to get some bridges.  I like it.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[fancy seeing u here]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/02/day-number-13/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-02T22:52:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/02/day-number-13</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>The Active Record/Sinatra/SQLite collabo.. wait, did we start it yesterday or fresh today?  Who knows anymore.  I just had to check my own blog, to write my own blog.  Head in a fog, log, bog, smog, brog.  Today was fun.  We made weird worlds, and I put chips and salsa everywhere, and David put guac, and Nimit hi-jacked my macbook like a Somali pirate and I&rsquo;m that new Tom Hanks movie where it&rsquo;s stressful and he grows a beard and keeps order over his seamen.  Surely persistence and the drive to discover is how you learn (so that&rsquo;s how you get good at things!).</p>

<p>Week 3 of the program, rolling along &ndash; thinking that we are already 25% of the way through the course, puts the fear in me like a lake of fire/gnashing of teeth next to the devil could never instill.  YOU ARE ALREADY &frac14; OF THE WAY THROUGH WITH YOUR WEB DEV IMMERSIVE SOON YOU WILL TAKE THE SKILLS YOU HAVE ACQUIRED FIND A JOB AND START WORKING WITH SAID SKILLS ON THE DAILY FOR MONEY.  This statement, is so fucking scary, it could be used in your favor to convert me to any religion/religions/causes/cults/sex-cults/porno-cage-dungeons of your heart&rsquo;s desire.  Yes, I will do porn if you just keep yelling that sentence at me.  I&rsquo;m so scared, yes, I&rsquo;m ready to shoot!!</p>

<p>In less scary news, or actually, rather debatable, check out what I made at school today mama!</p>

<p><a href="https://dry-tundra-6501.herokuapp.com/person/new">https://dry-tundra-6501.herokuapp.com/person/new</a></p>

<p>Come on in, have some chips n salsa in the foyer, kick up a shoe or two, pee in my double golden toilets (made of real gold, not that plated stuff), take a bounce or three in my double moon bounces, and check out some real meat in the dry-age-room/muscle dungeon.  But only if you dare.  Don&rsquo;t eat spaghetti squash in front of your keyboard while you explore these wormholes either, soldier.  Also, go ahead, put in your name (I&rsquo;ll never see it), create some rooms and add items to your heart&rsquo;s content (I will see these), and make some connections between those rooms to keep Wenson Stack World spicier than a mala pepper gone down the wrong throat path.</p>

<p>Don&rsquo;t be shy.  Here, to help things along, I&rsquo;ll tell/show you about myself.</p>

<p><img src="http://mayaday.files.wordpress.com/2010/03/funny-asian-face.jpg" title="JACKSON FROLIC" alt="Jackson Frolic" /></p>

<p>name:  Jackson Frolic <br>
description:  gum drops and jelly breams!<br><br></p>

<p>** breams are a type of fish like a snapper.  i kno how 2 type ohkay</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[day n nite]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/01/day-number-12/"/>
		<updated>2013-10-01T23:00:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/10/01/day-number-12</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>Today, we had our 3rd Fullstack Dinner, and it was pizza.  Grandma&rsquo;s pizza, Grandpa&rsquo;s pizza, White pizza, mushroom pizza (which no one touched inexplicably) &ndash; the pizza game be diversified.  The day was one with a good flow &ndash; we first learned about the internets.  The internets is busy, and it keeps passing stuff back and forth like basketball drills to keep us seeing things and un-revolty.  The US government was down today (effing ridiculous), but hey, it&rsquo;s fine when you can watch people do things on Brobible.com (mind sanitize).</p>

<iframe src="http://wensontsai.github.io//player.vimeo.com/video/14570497" width="500" height="375" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe>


<p> <p><a href="http://vimeo.com/14570497">Packet Flight: RickRoll @ 12X</a> from <a href="http://vimeo.com/carlosb">Carlos Bueno</a> on <a href="https://vimeo.com">Vimeo</a>.</p></p>

<p>Then we moved on to designing this multi-room portal site pulling in Sinatra, Rails(Active Record), SQL, and HTML/CSS which was pretty cool, cause it lets people come onto your site, and then create a room and name things.  Of course, the first room I named was the toilet, because every good space including a wormhole, needs a toilet (keep it hyperspace-clean, son!).  My butt cheeks be allergic to anything that&rsquo;s not gold even when I&rsquo;m space-dimensional-contiuum-irrespective-morphing/traveling.</p>

<p><img src="http://maison.trouvetout.ca/wp-content/uploads/2012/04/hong-kon-golden-toilet1.jpg" title="golden toilet" alt="golden toilet" /></p>

<p>I went back in time to fetch a 24k gold spouted butt-washer add-on with adjustable pressure/temperature controls.  Worth the risk of having to fight dinosaurs/aliens/zombies.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
	<entry>
		
			<title type="html"><![CDATA[death of pig-latin]]></title>
		
		<link href="http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/28/day-number-10/"/>
		<updated>2013-09-28T16:18:00-04:00</updated>
		<id>http://wensontsai.github.io/blog/2013/09/28/day-number-10</id>
		<content type="html">
			<![CDATA[
				
					<p></p>
				
			]]>
			<![CDATA[<p>I thought it would take me the next 5 years of my life, but with a shit-ton of help and explanation, failed thought process/approaches, hipchat support, sacrifice of a saturday, housecat jealousy, pure grudgery sprinkled on top, I re-wrote the code for the pig-latin testfirst.org problem, got it to work, and also understand it.</p>

<p>Arrays to strings to arrays to arrays to strings to goddamnit computer, why cant you just think the way I think, and we can be friends and share the same underpants?  You don&rsquo;t wear underpants.</p>

<p>Pig-Latin is dead!!</p>

<p>5 years of life has come back to me, and now I&rsquo;m thinking of skipping off to enjoy a Saturday night instead of working all the way through.  I am not a computer &ndash; just yet.</p>
]]>
		</content>
	</entry>
	
</feed>
